<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>personal on Meg Risdal</title>
    <link>https://www.meg.dev/tags/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in personal on Meg Risdal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>hello@meg.dev (Meg Risdal)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>hello@meg.dev (Meg Risdal)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 22:49:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.meg.dev/tags/personal/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Year in Review, 2021</title>
      <link>https://www.meg.dev/posts/my-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 22:49:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>hello@meg.dev (Meg Risdal)</author>
      <guid>https://www.meg.dev/posts/my-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-year-in-review-2021&#34;&gt;My Year in Review, 2021&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my third annual Meg’s year-in-review post (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://mrisdal.github.io/blog/posts/my-2020/&#34;&gt;2020&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://mrisdal.github.io/blog/posts/my-2019/&#34;&gt;2019&lt;/a&gt;) and what’s my first blog post in all of 2021. Eek. Haven’t made much time for writing, unfortunately; it’s been a much busier, happier year than 2020 was! Unlike 2020 which I spent in a monotonous, depressing “comfort zone” (the pandemic obviously didn’t help), this year I really took back control of my happiness. 10/10 recommend. Here are some highlights:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Got a divorce! Thank you everyone who supported me through this. It was amicable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saw friends in person again. Parties, hikes, movies, live music, plays, bars, lunches, dinners, travel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally I visited my family in Minnesota. And saw my parents in LA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Started to lead Product at Kaggle … for now. I declined an offer to be permanent Head of Product since I’m not keen to start people management as our team grows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bought a new bike and started to exercise more regularly and go for walks every day (though lately hasn’t been great apart from some hikes–need to make a New Year’s resolution).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created and hosted a super successful data science game show called &lt;a href=&#34;https://towardsdatascience.com/three-reasons-to-watch-sliced-a-real-time-data-science-competition-8d5212ccf988&#34;&gt;SLICED&lt;/a&gt; on Twitch with my friend Nick Wan!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Met a Canadian from my Among Us gaming group (thanks &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/nickwan&#34;&gt;Nick&lt;/a&gt;!) and fell completely in love. I’ve honestly never been happier or felt luckier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visited Toronto (twice) and Banff and made even more future plans to travel and be together with this person.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Started to play chess (umm, but now only puzzles), Scrabble, and learn Japanese on Duolingo as well as Cantonese with my new partner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I stopped drinking so much alcohol. I haven’t stopped drinking completely, but I used to keep beer at home and drink most days and now I don’t do that. I can’t say I feel any different, but it still feels like a healthy choice regardless.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And the final big one: I decided to move to Toronto! When I moved to LA in 2017, I thought it could be forever. But through the fires in the summer of 2020, I began to feel I couldn&amp;rsquo;t make it my permanent home. Still, I&amp;rsquo;m moving sooner than expected, but I&amp;rsquo;m following my heart (and bringing my mind with me). Toronto will define my 2022.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: Sorry this post is so late!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;top-film&#34;&gt;Top film&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;titane-2021&#34;&gt;Titane (2021)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterboxd.com/film/titane/&#34;&gt;Titane (2021)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; was this year’s Palme d’or winner and Meg’s most highly anticipated movie of the year. It premiered in LA when I was in Toronto and it played at the Toronto International Film Festival when I was in LA, so it kept escaping me but I finally managed to see it at The Alamo Drafthouse in DTLA. The director, Julia Ducournau, also directed &lt;a href=&#34;https://letterboxd.com/film/raw-2016/&#34;&gt;Raw (2016)&lt;/a&gt; which I saw and absolutely loved when I lived in Pittsburgh, PA. An elderly couple walked out of the theater during a particularly intense scene and I was craving the same corporeal sexual shock in her latest film Titane. It was very satisfying and unexpectedly heartwarming and funny (honestly, I thought there would be more sex with cars in the movie, though). Anyway, I knew I’d love the movie straight away when it began with the main protagonist murdering a man who attempted to sexually assault her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other movies that were highlights this year:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterboxd.com/film/dune-2021/&#34;&gt;Dune (2021)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; which I saw with my parents when they visited me in LA. I got tickets to see it at the TCL Chinese Theater IMAX. My mom wanted to see a director’s Q&amp;amp;A, but this is the best I could manage (there was a director’s Q&amp;amp;A a couple of weeks later, sigh).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterboxd.com/film/booksmart/&#34;&gt;Booksmart (2019)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is a movie I’ve seen 3 or 4 times at this point. It’s perfect?! It’s on my list because some of us from the Among Us gaming group started watching movies together and we picked this one weekend. I was desperate for my boyfriend to watch it with us because I knew he’d love it. And he did, which made me so happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still watched &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterboxd.com/film/akira/&#34;&gt;Akira (1988)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; a ton this year (it was my “movie of the year” last year), so it’s still on my list as a highlight of course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;top-record&#34;&gt;Top record&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly I didn’t listen to much new music this year, sorry. I did get to see some live music this year, though, which was great. So I’m going to cheat and write about that instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ween&lt;/strong&gt;. Ween is special to me because I first listened to them while on a week-long road trip with my sister in Australia. Her new boyfriend at the time (they’re still together!) made us a “mixtape” for our car ride that featured a lot of Ween. So it’s like our sister thing now. We saw them in St. Paul, MN in 2018. This past August we saw them again at Surly Brewing also in Minnesota. It was amazing. I remember the feeling of buying the tickets back in February 2021 before getting vaccinated. The founded optimism was such an incredible feeling. And it was made even more gratifying when it actually came to fruition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deafheaven&lt;/strong&gt;. I saw Deafheaven in 2019 in LA and I was excited to see them again at The Ace Hotel in DTLA this past fall. I went by myself. The venue was totally gorgeous, would definitely go back. The show was okay. Can’t say I adore their 100% clean vocal thing as they played every song from their new album, Infinite Granite. But hey I’ll take pretty much any live music at this point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dead and Company&lt;/strong&gt;. My parents came to visit LA so they could see Dead and Company at The Hollywood Bowl for three nights on Halloween weekend. This was a “bucket list” experience for my dad so that was special. If you don’t know, my dad is an enormous Deadhead. I was invited to join him for one of the nights which was fun. Definitely a nostalgia thing for me since I grew up listening to The Dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opeth&lt;/strong&gt;. The last music I saw in 2021 was Opeth at The Palladium in December just a couple days after getting back from Banff, Alberta. I caught up with a friend beforehand at the same bar we went to before their last LA show immediately before the pandemic lockdown. So we were a bit nervous about triggering a Groundhog Day effect (uhh, I even wore the same outfit as in 2020).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;top-song&#34;&gt;Top song&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, let’s go. My favorite band, &lt;a href=&#34;https://porcupinetree.com/&#34;&gt;Porcupine Tree&lt;/a&gt;, is reuniting and I couldn’t be happier about it. I got into them around 2006 and they broke up just a few years later. I never got to see them live (although I have seen Steven Wilson live a few times). They put out a single, Harridan, which to be honest is so good. It’s genuine Porcupine Tree and it’s making me so hyped for an album and upcoming tour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
    &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/AW5v4Ohxk5k&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;top-book&#34;&gt;Top book&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I, uhh, didn’t really read any good books in 2021. A few years ago I switched to audiobooks which hugely increased the number of books I would “read”. But ever since I stopped commuting to work, I’ve listened to far fewer audiobooks. I’ve also completely swapped to listening to podcasts before bed each night. So yeah. I canceled my Audible subscription.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;top-game&#34;&gt;Top game&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year’s top game has to go to a classic: Scrabble! I played a lot more games this year compared to the previous year, so it was hard to choose. Scrabble was also a late entry to 2021. My partner and I just started playing together in September or so after I put out a call on Twitter for non-ad-riddled Scrabble apps and discovered &lt;a href=&#34;https://woogles.io/&#34;&gt;Woogles.io&lt;/a&gt;. It’s basically chess.com but for Scrabble and we love it. We play every night and it’s a perfect long-distance relationship ritual. He’s also the first guy I’ve dated who can beat me, which I’m going to interpret as being romantically significant. We even collaborated on a project to use their undocumented API to grab our game data and analyze it. This turned into a Community Competition on Kaggle: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com/c/scrabble-point-value&#34;&gt;Scrabble Point Value&lt;/a&gt;. Basically, it’s brought me a ton of joy this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other top games for me in 2021:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Among Us&lt;/strong&gt;. I picked this as my game of the year last year and honestly I was tempted to pick it again this year. At the very end of 2020 I had just started to play at work and maybe once or twice with this gaming group online. But it was really this year that we played a ton (every Saturday for a solid half year). Plus, me and the guy I’m now dating even hand-tracked our game stats to analyze later and obviously it’s how we met in the first place. I never thought I’d meet someone and fall in love online playing a video game. What is this, 2008? Anyway, Among Us will always have a special place in my heart now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/strong&gt;. Yes, I played this game on my Stadia when it came out and had zero issues, sucker! I’m actually replaying this right now. It’s totally … okay? It’s fine. That’s right, I still use my Stadia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It Takes Two&lt;/strong&gt;. Me and my friend Nick played this around the time that we were working on SLICED! It’s super cute and creative and a lot of fun. And it just won Game of the Year at The Game Awards!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chess&lt;/strong&gt;.  Also another super classic that I got back into during the pandemic. Briefly I got into playing some actual games, but I’ll be honest I found it extremely anxiety-inducing and couldn’t handle it. So now I just do chess puzzles which I love. My boyfriend is also into chess and we puzzle battle just about every single day, too. I’ve even beaten him a few times!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;top-podcast-sort-of&#34;&gt;Top podcast (sort of)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve listened to more podcasts in 2021 than any year prior. I’ve mostly kept the same things as past years in my rotation: Darknet Diaries, Daniel and Jorge Explain the Universe, Sean Carroll’s Mindscape, 99% Invisible, and Stuff You Should Know, for example. To this, I’ve added a number of relationship / romantic podcasts which I won’t list here. But I did have a couple of podcast serials I listened to which I can recommend:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://crooked.com/podcast-series/wind-of-change/&#34;&gt;Wind of Change&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. This came out in 2020, but I listened to it in 2021 (haha pretty sure?).  It’s an investigation into the theory that the 1990s power ballad “Wind of Change” by Scorpion was written by the CIA during the collapse of the Soviet Union to be the anthem for the revolution during the collapse of the Soviet Union. If you like this, there’s also a cool Radiolab episode in their Mixtape series about the introduction of contemporary western music to China via Dakou, plastic scraps of trashed cassettes refurbished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wondery.com/shows/operator/&#34;&gt;Operator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. I’m listening to this right now. It’s about the rise and fall of the sex operator industry titan, American Telnet. There’s so many facets to this that make it a really fascinating story: marginalization of sex work, their technological innovations, and, well, another classic story of capitalist scandal and demise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;top-tv-show&#34;&gt;Top TV show&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also didn’t watch a ton of TV this year. Even more so than movies, I found I simply didn’t have the time or attention span to dedicate to an entire series. I could do 90 minutes here and there, but not three seasons of Succession (just kidding, I just started watching this). So most of my enjoyment came from more lighthearted, bite-sized affairs. This makes I Think You Should Leave (Season 2) my top pick for 2021. It’s so weird and brings me so much joy. If I can’t decide what to watch sometimes I just put on old episodes for comfort. How the jokes and language permeate my everyday thoughts has also been really satisfying.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7xS9Y_mjTjc&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other highlights include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pen15&lt;/strong&gt;. The creators and main characters of this show are pretty much exactly the same age as I am so this show is a major flashback to 5th grade for me. Its balance of levity and heartfelt sincerity are so wonderful especially in the latest season where they confront more serious topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Married at First Sight&lt;/strong&gt;. You might call this my guilty pleasure show. I’ve kind of given up on 90 Day Fiance in favor of MAFS full time. I just love the combination of romance and a social experiment like marrying a stranger at first sight. Another pandemic highlight for me, for example, was Love is Blind (go Cameron and Lauren forever!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reply&#34;&gt;Reply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow the conversation and discuss your favs on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Here&amp;#39;s my 2020 year in review where I talk about my fav movies, music, games, etc. &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/oUHQSC9aTo&#34;&gt;https://t.co/oUHQSC9aTo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; meg.ehh 🇨🇦 (@MeganRisdal) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MeganRisdal/status/1345895617139073024?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;January 4, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Year in Review, 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.meg.dev/posts/my-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 02:29:15 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>hello@meg.dev (Meg Risdal)</author>
      <guid>https://www.meg.dev/posts/my-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my second year-in-review post &lt;a href=&#34;https://mrisdal.github.io/blog/posts/my-2019/&#34;&gt;see my 2019 post&lt;/a&gt;. This year was much shittier than last year. That&amp;rsquo;s partly my fault and partly the fault of the pandemic, my bike getting stolen, etc. etc. So I think I spent most of this year in a &amp;ldquo;comfort zone&amp;rdquo; which was somewhat depressing and monotonous. There were some bright spots, though:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I started my new (old) job back at Kaggle which has been good&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My husband and I took a lovely vacation to Hawaii right before the pandemic hit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I started cooking a lot more and haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten totally sick of it yet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MeganRisdal/status/1344482197999288323?s=20&#34;&gt;I began doing something like mentoring semi-regularly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve improved a lot at disconnecting from work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to socialize occasionally through things like horror movie club, playing Among Us, etc. but should probably make an effort to do more to not become even more isolated and weird in 2021 &amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, in my year-in-review post I just want to cover the media I consume. This year, I definitely binged on movies and video games and did a lot less reading or listening to music, sadly. I used to listen to a lot of audio books and music while driving (or biking &amp;hellip;) and did less of both of those this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;My 2020 in review (it was pretty shitty TBH ...)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;📽️ Film - Akira (1988)&lt;br&gt;🎶 Song - A Door Marked Summer, Steven Wilson (2017)&lt;br&gt;💽 Record - In Cauda Venenum, Opeth (2019)&lt;br&gt;📚 Book - Akira, Katsuhiro Otomo (1982-1990)&lt;br&gt;🎮 Game(s) - Among Us, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/acnh?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#acnh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/rdr2?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#rdr2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;🎙️ Podcast - Darknet Diaries&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; meg.ehh 🇨🇦 (@MeganRisdal) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MeganRisdal/status/1345894613375098880?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;January 4, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;top-film&#34;&gt;Top film&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;akira-1988&#34;&gt;Akira (1988)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, if you&amp;rsquo;ve been following me on Twitter it comes as no surprise that this is my top film of the year. Towards the end of the year, I went on a 30-day posting rampage on Twitter, sharing just about anything and everything Akira-related that came to my mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But truly I love this movie. I first saw it probably over 15 years ago and it&amp;rsquo;s been one of my favorites since. For a while I had a tradition of watching it every year around new year&amp;rsquo;s. This year, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MeganRisdal/status/1330081766795849729&#34;&gt;a thread I randomly created on Twitter featuring Akira &amp;ldquo;bike slide&amp;rdquo; homages&lt;/a&gt; kicked off my most recent binge. Instead of linking a trailer below, I&amp;rsquo;ll share one of my favorites among the many Akira-related YouTube videos I&amp;rsquo;ve watched over the past couple of months:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2ltgr21jMag&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love Akira because it&amp;rsquo;s just a perfect mixture of everything I dig: science fiction, body horror, post-apocalypse, violence and gore (but not like, over-the-top), corruption, and gorgeous art. The story is a bit challenging to follow until you&amp;rsquo;ve seen it a few times and the dialog is kind of awkward in my opinion (maybe it&amp;rsquo;s the English translation?), but otherwise it doesn&amp;rsquo;t miss. There&amp;rsquo;s so much depth and so many layers to enjoy about Akira, too. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s its endless themes, its cultural impact, or its utterly astonishing animation, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot to appreciate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could obviously go on but I&amp;rsquo;ll leave it there. I know my tweetstorms about Akira were probably  really annoying to a lot of people (myself included at times), but I hope at least one or two of my followers maybe checked out the film and / or manga as a result &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, let&amp;rsquo;s keep this moving. This year, I managed to keep my &lt;a href=&#34;https://letterboxd.com/mrisdal/films/diary/&#34;&gt;Letterboxd&lt;/a&gt; up-to-date so you can see everything I watched (and what I rated it). I even shelled out for a &amp;ldquo;pro&amp;rdquo; subscription since I think it&amp;rsquo;s a great service. Here are some other films I enjoyed last year:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Elephant Man&lt;/em&gt; (1980) - WHY did I put off watching this movie for so long &amp;ndash; truly excellent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bartleby&lt;/em&gt; (2001) - &amp;ldquo;I would prefer not to&amp;rdquo; is a real mood&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Invisible Man&lt;/em&gt; (2020) - The last movie I saw in a theater (at the Arclight Dome in Hollywood!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;top-record&#34;&gt;Top record&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-cauda-venenum---opeth-2019&#34;&gt;In Cauda Venenum - Opeth (2019)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like I said earlier, I sadly didn&amp;rsquo;t discover or listen to a lot of new music in 2020. Right before the pandemic hit, my husband and I had started to go to more small local shows, so maybe things might have been different in an alternate timeline. One nice new album, though, was Opeth&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;In Cauda Venenum&lt;/em&gt;. We were eager to buy the record and swung by Amoeba Records in Hollywood to try to buy it after it was released several times. Each time they didn&amp;rsquo;t have it in stock yet. When they finally got their shipment in, we picked up the Swedish version. We get home and play it and it turns out it&amp;rsquo;s the English version. Oh well!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/5Ko4_eO2tiU&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also had the pleasure of seeing Opeth live TWICE. Well, once was a live show at the Palladium which was one of my last outings of 2020. And the other time (which may have actually happened in 2019, not sure) was seeing Mikael and friends at a bar/restaurant in Hollywood. We were seated across from them! Funnily, I had just earlier that day complained to my husband that they were doing a show in Las Vegas and not LA that weekend &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;top-song&#34;&gt;Top song&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-door-marked-summer-steven-wilson-2017&#34;&gt;A Door Marked Summer, Steven Wilson (2017)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the song of 2020 for me because every single time I&amp;rsquo;m checking my audio on my computer or whatever, I test it by playing this on YouTube. With mandatory work from home, I guess I frequently checked my audio this year because I&amp;rsquo;ve listened to this song a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But seriously, it&amp;rsquo;s a beautiful song. It&amp;rsquo;s an outtake from his solo album &lt;em&gt;To The Bone&lt;/em&gt; (2017) and it sounds a LOT more like &lt;em&gt;Porcupine Tree&lt;/em&gt; than his solo stuff or the rest of the album. Steven Wilson has some of the best b-sides / outtakes, and this is definitely no exception. The moment at 5:26 gets me every time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2IIx6g_2DsE&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of amazing b-sides / outtakes by Steven Wilson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Meantime (In Absentia)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Drown with Me (In Absentia)&lt;/em&gt; (how was this not on the original album?!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/porcupinetree/comments/60aqqz/bsides_and_outtakes/&#34;&gt;full list&lt;/a&gt; I found on Reddit if you&amp;rsquo;re interested (probably not).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;book&#34;&gt;Book&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;akira-katsuhiro-otomo-1982-1990&#34;&gt;Akira, Katsuhiro Otomo (1982-1990)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surprise, my book of the year is the &lt;em&gt;Akira&lt;/em&gt; manga.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My amazing husband bought me the epic &lt;em&gt;35th anniversary Akira manga box set&lt;/em&gt; for my birthday this year. And I read all 2k+ pages / 6 volumes in a single weekend. For many years I&amp;rsquo;ve been tempted to buy the manga. Every time my husband and I would be browsing some used bookstore, I&amp;rsquo;d check out to see if they had the complete manga. But I never quite mustered up enough, umm, money? to make a purchase (I think I must have spent more time in used bookstores when I was a grad student). I&amp;rsquo;m glad I waited for this edition! It&amp;rsquo;s all in the original right-to-left layout with sound effects in Japanese and it comes in a cool box which looks pretty handsome on one of our bookshelves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I&amp;rsquo;ve never read a manga prior to this one and obviously I was blown away! The artwork is something I could absorb for hours (I&amp;rsquo;ve downloaded so many of my favorites scans to my phone to admire &amp;hellip; or, uhh, post on Twitter). The story is obviously much, much more elaborate than the film (although I think the film did a good job of condensing) and the characters as you know them totally change. Kaneda is even more so just goofy comic relief (and his friendship with Tetsuo) and the real badass is Kei (IMO). Tetsuo is a bratty megalomaniac in the film and I, uhh, guess he still is in the manga, but his transformation is much richer and way, way more disturbing. Akira is actually alive in the manga (not that he says or does much, though) and Kai is still the cutest ever. As in the film, I found the dialog a bit stilted (but, again, I suspect that&amp;rsquo;s partly due to the translation?). I&amp;rsquo;m still confused by Ryu! What&amp;rsquo;s his deal!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/pw/ACtC-3cd2jw5_QoSMifSjm-89OeJLOyfTSPLz9m-xmtEKPvpW6d49K_T2ukXa1rt0jVvcFjvqaCZmm_NvMNGP3RgDNOyJVzgNpoCAJOoxJJGV-7z5gOULVId4r6Eg-Ui7h2O9rgf70XP7ZNnIJQuPJSMb6dtew=w800-h567-no&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;game&#34;&gt;Game&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;among-us-2018&#34;&gt;Among Us (2018)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was pretty hard to pick a game for 2020 since I spent so much time playing video games. I decide to go with &lt;em&gt;Among Us&lt;/em&gt; because it surprised me the most. I&amp;rsquo;m not normally a fan of deception type games. I know this because my Kaggle coworkers are BIG into deception games like &lt;em&gt;One Night Werewolf&lt;/em&gt; so I think I&amp;rsquo;ve played my fair share during our team offsites. But fact is I&amp;rsquo;m a seriously TERRIBLE LIAR. I don&amp;rsquo;t even like doing deceptive things, much less trying to cover myself up. I generally think this is a positive character trait, but anyhow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it surprised me when I enjoyed this game so much when we played during a Kaggle team remote &amp;ldquo;offsite&amp;rdquo; this year. The actual 2D game aspect of it adds a lot that I appreciate &amp;hellip; like just being able to do some innocent tasks and then enjoy other people who are better than me at deception try to work things out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/NSJ4cESNQfE&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Among Us&lt;/em&gt; definitely did NOT account for a large share of the time I spent playing video games in 2020, though. Here&amp;rsquo;s what else I played&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zelda Breath of the Wild&lt;/em&gt; - My first Zelda game apart from the time in high school a friend made me beat the final boss in a different series or whatever just so I could credibly say I had played Zelda&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Animal Crossing New Horizons&lt;/em&gt; - Also my first &lt;em&gt;Animal Crossing&lt;/em&gt; which I enjoyed a lot for a while but now I dread the thought of going back to my island&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Red Dead Redemption 2&lt;/em&gt; - I LOVE open world games like Skyrim so I knew it was a matter of time I checked this out (also why I bought Stadia which is great so far!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;podcast&#34;&gt;Podcast&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;darknet-diaries-2008-2019&#34;&gt;Darknet Diaries (2008-2019)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I honestly can&amp;rsquo;t remember how I discovered &lt;em&gt;Darknet Diaries&lt;/em&gt; by Jack Rhysider, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been really enjoying it so far and highly recommend it if you&amp;rsquo;re remotely interested in cybercrime, hackers, etc. My favorite episode was &lt;a href=&#34;https://darknetdiaries.com/episode/54/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;NotPetya&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I added a few more things to my regular podcast rotation which includes &lt;em&gt;SYSK&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;99% Invisible&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Mindscape&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Daniel and Jorge Explain the Universe&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Radiolab&lt;/em&gt; (don&amp;rsquo;t judge me) among some others, but honestly not too much. I&amp;rsquo;d be happy to hear some suggestions for what I should check out next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reply&#34;&gt;Reply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow the conversation and discuss your favs on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Here&amp;#39;s my 2020 year in review where I talk about my fav movies, music, games, etc. &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/oUHQSC9aTo&#34;&gt;https://t.co/oUHQSC9aTo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; meg.ehh 🇨🇦 (@MeganRisdal) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MeganRisdal/status/1345895617139073024?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;January 4, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be aggressive, be be aggressive. But how aggressive?</title>
      <link>https://www.meg.dev/posts/be-aggressive/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 19:47:01 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>hello@meg.dev (Meg Risdal)</author>
      <guid>https://www.meg.dev/posts/be-aggressive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week I asked for feedback on something I wrote from a trusted colleague. My audience was larger than usual for me and 100% men (as far as I knew). Although I&amp;rsquo;m already pretty confident in my prose-writing skills, I felt greater than usual pressure to make a compelling, tight story. I wanted what I wrote to sound authoritative and well informed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My colleague gave me great constructive feedback and overall really liked what I wrote. Except one spot where I came across as harsh and somewhat arrogant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cringed. &lt;em&gt;I know, I know&lt;/em&gt;. When drafting that particular point, I had literally thought to myself (knowing that I can tend to hedge too much) &amp;ldquo;Okay, try to sound very assertive and &lt;em&gt;masculine&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;rdquo; It wasn&amp;rsquo;t me. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t my style or my voice. And it ended up sounding too abrasive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, easy enough fix. I softened the language and sent it off to my co-authors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, I kept thinking about this. It really made me realize how I&amp;rsquo;m constantly monitoring how I speak and write to perfectly balance cold authority and warm personability. Whether I&amp;rsquo;m self conscious about the number of &amp;ldquo;:)&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;!&amp;rdquo; that I use in an email or my willingness to admit &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know&amp;rdquo; in a meeting, it&amp;rsquo;s a perpetual struggle against my natural tendencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing is, I rarely actually feel 100% confident. But I know that my male counterparts, even when they &lt;em&gt;sound&lt;/em&gt; totally (and sometimes absurdly) sure of themselves, they can&amp;rsquo;t possibly be so certain either! So I try to put myself in their state of mind and just fake it. If I don&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;sound technical enough&amp;rdquo;, I&amp;rsquo;d rather actually become more competent than merely sound like it, for example. That&amp;rsquo;s where my energy goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t really like games, either, where I have to put on a guise and deceive my audience. And obviously it can be backfire coming from a woman. A woman product manager without a background in software engineering. But I don&amp;rsquo;t have patience for that and I prefer to be my honest, authentic self.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So after dwelling on this for a couple of days, I think I&amp;rsquo;ve come up with a way to determine how to strike the right tone. I&amp;rsquo;ll rehearse for my husband. I&amp;rsquo;m 100% comfortable and safe saying what I truthfully believe in a confident way to him. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how this strategy works for me the next time I&amp;rsquo;m stuck on how to phrase something in an authoritative way that still sounds like me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, this isn&amp;rsquo;t really a theory informed blog post. It could be if I spent some minutes doing some research on gendered language in the workplace and maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll do that later. Even though as a linguist I feel a bit guilty about that, for now I wanted the gratification of finally publishing a new blog post after a few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you decide how &amp;ldquo;aggressive&amp;rdquo; to be at work?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reply&#34;&gt;Reply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow the conversation and discuss on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;How aggressive should you be at work? &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/ws9uK0ZFaj&#34;&gt;https://t.co/ws9uK0ZFaj&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; meg.ehh 🇨🇦 (@MeganRisdal) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MeganRisdal/status/1274184503880060928?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;June 20, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Year in Review, 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.meg.dev/posts/my-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 02:29:15 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>hello@meg.dev (Meg Risdal)</author>
      <guid>https://www.meg.dev/posts/my-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my own year-in-review. What started as a dumb tweet has become a blog post because I&amp;rsquo;m between jobs. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;My 2019:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;📽️ Film - Society (1989)&lt;br&gt;🎶 Song - Sandwich, Marco Minnemann (2016)&lt;br&gt;💽 Record - In the Court of the Crimson King (50th anniversary) King Crimson (2019)&lt;br&gt;📚 Book - Our Mathematical Universe, Max Tegmark (2014)&lt;br&gt;🎮 Game - Untitled Goose (2019)&lt;br&gt;🎙️ Podcast - SYSK (2008-2019)&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; meg.ehh 🇨🇦 (@MeganRisdal) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MeganRisdal/status/1204635323474432003?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;December 11, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;top-film&#34;&gt;Top film&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;society-1989&#34;&gt;Society (1989)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My husband had described &lt;em&gt;Society&lt;/em&gt; (dir, Brian Yuzna) to me a few years ago and I don&amp;rsquo;t think I really absorbed much because it didn&amp;rsquo;t seem believable or something. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty trippy! Here&amp;rsquo;s the snippet from Wikipedia:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Beverly Hills teen (Billy Warlock) discovers his parents are part of a gruesome orgy cult for the social elite.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a big fan of body horror, though, I knew I had to see it at some point This year (probably during &lt;em&gt;Beyond Fest&lt;/em&gt;) we had the fortune of seeing it at &lt;em&gt;The Egyptian Theater&lt;/em&gt; in Hollywood. It&amp;rsquo;s great. Wicked! Believe it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/inrBU8juGI8&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I only recently started using &lt;a href=&#34;https://letterboxd.com/mrisdal/films/diary/&#34;&gt;Letterboxd&lt;/a&gt; again to track my films, but some other good ones from this year:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Greener Grass&lt;/em&gt; (2019) - David Lynch plus SNL. Yes? Yes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Knives Out&lt;/em&gt; (2019) - Just a lot of fun!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;top-record&#34;&gt;Top record&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-the-court-of-the-crimson-king-50th-anniversary---king-crimson-2019&#34;&gt;In the Court of the Crimson King, 50th anniversary - King Crimson (2019)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a friend in college who was obsessed with &lt;em&gt;King Crimson&lt;/em&gt;. I didn&amp;rsquo;t get much into them myself at the time, but they were an &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/King_Crimson#Influence&#34;&gt;influence&lt;/a&gt; on basically everything else I listen to. &lt;em&gt;Porcupine Tree&lt;/em&gt; / &lt;em&gt;Steven Wilson&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Mars Volta&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Opeth&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Between the Buried and Me&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Mastodon&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Oranssi Pazuzu&lt;/em&gt;, etc. etc. etc. You get it. Oh, and one of the
three (3) drummers in their current line-up is Gavin Harrison, drummer for &lt;em&gt;Porcupine Tree&lt;/em&gt; (since broken-up).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, when &lt;em&gt;King Crimson&lt;/em&gt; were on their 50th anniversary tour and making a stop at &lt;em&gt;The Greek Theater&lt;/em&gt; in Los Angeles, of course I had to go out of reverence. Wow. I was totally and completely blown away. Despite the tourist next to me using his phone / camera (a BIG no-no for Robert Fripp). Perhaps life-changing in that I&amp;rsquo;ve been obsessively listening to &lt;em&gt;KC&lt;/em&gt; ever since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, my favorite album is the 50th anniversary remix of &lt;em&gt;In the Court of the Crimson King&lt;/em&gt;. The remix is done by Steven Wilson (of course). And &lt;em&gt;Epitaph&lt;/em&gt; is still (sadly) the best song for these times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowledge is a deadly friend&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If no one sets the rules&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fate of all mankind, I see&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is in the hands of fools&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not from this album of course, but here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Starless&lt;/em&gt; live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/FhKJgqxNDD8&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other music I listened to a lot of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Agalloch&lt;/em&gt; - I discovered them this year &amp;hellip; so GOOD.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Aristocrats&lt;/em&gt; - Guthrie Govan is amazing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deafheaven&lt;/em&gt; - So different, but gorgeous warm black metal feels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;top-song&#34;&gt;Top song&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sandwich-marco-minnemann-2016&#34;&gt;Sandwich, Marco Minnemann (2016)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This song is just fun. Any time it pops into my head (which to the dismay of my husband is probably too often) I have to play it. Marco Minnemann is a great drummer. Maybe you&amp;rsquo;ve heard of him. He&amp;rsquo;s associated with &lt;em&gt;Steven Wilson&amp;rsquo;s band&lt;/em&gt; (not anymore, but it&amp;rsquo;s how I came to know him), &lt;em&gt;Necrophagist&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Aristocrats&lt;/em&gt;, and he auditioned for &lt;em&gt;Dream Theater&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out the music video for &lt;em&gt;Sandwich&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t you know how to eat a sandwich?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wNjrj3BFlXc&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other top songs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Epitaph, King Crimson&lt;/em&gt; - Already mentioned but bears rementioning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Black Lake Niðstång, Agalloch&lt;/em&gt; - It&amp;rsquo;s worth 17 minutes. Some of the most soulful black metal screaming of life (death?).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;book&#34;&gt;Book&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;our-mathematical-universe-max-tegmark-2014&#34;&gt;Our Mathematical Universe, Max Tegmark (2014)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of years ago I caved and started listening to audiobooks. This plus a pair of bluetooth headphones I like (Jabra Elite 65t) has led to a big increase in the number of books I manage to &amp;ldquo;read&amp;rdquo; each year. It definitely makes up for the guilty feelings I harbor for not being a legitimate book snob. Just kidding. I don&amp;rsquo;t care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this year my favorite book is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Our-Mathematical-Universe-Ultimate-Reality/dp/0307599809&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our Mathematical Universe&lt;/em&gt; by Max Tegmark&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m a pretty big pop astronomy / physics nerd, and this book is so out there it blew my mind. In so many ways. What do &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; physicists think of this book?! If you&amp;rsquo;re into multiverses, reality, consciousness, and wild speculation, check it out. If you want just a taste, Max Tegmark made a recent appearance on Sean Carroll&amp;rsquo;s podcast, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.preposterousuniverse.com/podcast/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mindscape&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.preposterousuniverse.com/podcast/2019/12/02/75-max-tegmark-on-reality-simulation-and-the-multiverse/&#34;&gt;Episode #75&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://art19.com/shows/sean-carrolls-mindscape/episodes/f48de2b5-e16e-4d09-bc56-a34fb5fcecd3/embed?theme=dark-blue&#34; style=&#34;width: 100%; height: 200px; border: 0 none;&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from physics, I really love a good corporate scandal novel (yes, &lt;em&gt;Bad Blood&lt;/em&gt;, yes, &lt;em&gt;Super Pumped&lt;/em&gt;), so next year I expect my favorite book will be about WeWork (fingers crossed).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;game&#34;&gt;Game&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;untitled-goose-2019&#34;&gt;Untitled Goose (2019)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What more do I need to say?! &lt;em&gt;Untitled Goose&lt;/em&gt; was a lot of fun. I had a hard time picking between this and &lt;em&gt;Katamari Reroll&lt;/em&gt;. Delightfulness and ease-of-play were the things that tipped things in favor of the goose for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9STHqt_vsCc&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some other games worth mentioning:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Skyrim&lt;/em&gt; - Whenever I get a new gaming system I buy &lt;em&gt;Skyrim&lt;/em&gt;. I will never not play this game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Super Smash Bros Ultimate&lt;/em&gt; - This was a lot of fun to play with my husband&amp;rsquo;s son (11yo).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pokemon Sword&lt;/em&gt; - I just started playing this! It&amp;rsquo;s a lot of fun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;podcast&#34;&gt;Podcast&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;stuff-you-should-know-2008-2019&#34;&gt;Stuff You Should Know (2008-2019)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to this year I hadn&amp;rsquo;t listened to a ton of podcasts since college. What changed? Not sure, but &lt;em&gt;Stuff You Should Know&lt;/em&gt; is now a staple for me. My husband don&amp;rsquo;t have overlapping tastes really except we can both get into a random &lt;em&gt;SYSK&lt;/em&gt; episode about jellyfish on our way to &lt;em&gt;The Dynasty Typewriter&lt;/em&gt; to see &lt;em&gt;Harmontown&lt;/em&gt; (a podcast I don&amp;rsquo;t listen to that we would go see live). We also listened to a bunch of episodes on our mini-roadtrip between LA and Santa Cruz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fVZyh5W63rM&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a couple of other podcasts I got into:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jorge and Daniel Explain the Universe&lt;/em&gt; - Just fun! Remember, I&amp;rsquo;m a pop-physics nerd.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Radiolab&amp;rsquo;s More Perfect&lt;/em&gt; - I devoured this in a couple of weeks and I&amp;rsquo;m sad there aren&amp;rsquo;t new ones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reply&#34;&gt;Reply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow the conversation and discuss your favs on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Here&amp;#39;s my fav films, music, and more in my year in review! &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/yS1H1wztq6&#34;&gt;https://t.co/yS1H1wztq6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; meg.ehh 🇨🇦 (@MeganRisdal) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MeganRisdal/status/1204680916162891776?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;December 11, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Hobbies</title>
      <link>https://www.meg.dev/posts/new-hobbies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 17:53:46 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>hello@meg.dev (Meg Risdal)</author>
      <guid>https://www.meg.dev/posts/new-hobbies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks ago I tweeted that I wanted to explore new hobbies. For the past couple of years, I&amp;rsquo;ve engrossed myself in a job I love. My career development has been really rewarding professionally, but lately I&amp;rsquo;ve felt personally underdeveloped. My current hobbies include seeing movies (especially horror and sci-fi) and exploring my new home of Los Angeles (biking, hiking, and of course eating). While these things are fun, I feel like I could be doing and &lt;em&gt;creating&lt;/em&gt; so much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems like everyone I know is into some really awesome hobbies: kite surfing, beekeeping, knitting, curling, trapeze, etc. etc. And I used to do some cool things myself: play oboe, sing in a Georgian folk choir, mountain bike. But lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been filling my time with a lot of Netflix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I decided to poll my cooler-than-me Twitter audience. What are some interesting hobby ideas I can try out on weekends?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;I just had the idea to try one totally new hobby per week. Or maybe every other week... What are some cheap, cool weekend hobbies you like? 🎨🖌️🌱🎹📝&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(The plant emoji obviously means fairy gardening.)&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; meg.ehh 🇨🇦 (@MeganRisdal) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MeganRisdal/status/1041602406172123136?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;September 17, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideas flooded in! In case you might be inspired to try something new yourself, here are all of the suggestions I received:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Juggling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Puzzles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Voxel Art (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.voxelmade.com/magicavoxel/&#34;&gt;MagicaVoxel&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kaggle Competitions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🍰&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Birdwatching&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sketching portraits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mod podge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skateboarding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cooking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manga/anime sketching&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start a local food and travel blog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meet new people from different cultures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ukele&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tango&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Martial arts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drawing painting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visit museums&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coffee/ice cream/chocolate tasting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paper crafts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Baking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wine tasting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn to make 3D polyhedra&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make notebooks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help local refugees&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teach English&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naturally, I ignored ALL of these suggestions. For my first hobby, I&amp;rsquo;m not straying far from my comfort zone (I am still in my sweats at home, after all)&amp;ndash;I&amp;rsquo;m creating this new personal website. Now, there&amp;rsquo;s a reason why I&amp;rsquo;m spending my first hobby project this way, of course. With this blog, I&amp;rsquo;ll now have a place for me to document my &amp;ldquo;new hobby&amp;rdquo; hobbies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, so that&amp;rsquo;s it for the meta-post. I hope you&amp;rsquo;ll look forward to my next!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reply&#34;&gt;Reply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow the conversation and discuss on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;New hobbies. &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/MFqPVrWitH&#34;&gt;https://t.co/MFqPVrWitH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; meg.ehh 🇨🇦 (@MeganRisdal) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MeganRisdal/status/1048815470126686209?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;October 7, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://www.meg.dev/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 15:51:11 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>hello@meg.dev (Meg Risdal)</author>
      <guid>https://www.meg.dev/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello world! I&amp;rsquo;m recreating my personal website using &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. Previously it was written in Bootstrap. I hope you enjoy the new look and layout.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>