<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>personal on Meg Risdal</title>
    <link>https://mrisdal.github.io/blog/tags/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in personal on Meg Risdal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 22:49:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mrisdal.github.io/blog/tags/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Year in Review, 2021</title>
      <link>https://mrisdal.github.io/blog/posts/my-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 22:49:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrisdal.github.io/blog/posts/my-2021/</guid>
      <description>My Year in Review, 2021 Welcome to my third annual Meg’s year-in-review post (see 2020 and 2019) and what’s my first blog post in all of 2021. Eek. Haven’t made much time for writing, unfortunately; it’s been a much busier, happier year than 2020 was! Unlike 2020 which I spent in a monotonous, depressing “comfort zone” (the pandemic obviously didn’t help), this year I really took back control of my happiness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Year in Review, 2020</title>
      <link>https://mrisdal.github.io/blog/posts/my-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 02:29:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrisdal.github.io/blog/posts/my-2020/</guid>
      <description>This is my second year-in-review post see my 2019 post. This year was much shittier than last year. That&amp;rsquo;s partly my fault and partly the fault of the pandemic, my bike getting stolen, etc. etc. So I think I spent most of this year in a &amp;ldquo;comfort zone&amp;rdquo; which was somewhat depressing and monotonous. There were some bright spots, though:
I started my new (old) job back at Kaggle which has been good My husband and I took a lovely vacation to Hawaii right before the pandemic hit I started cooking a lot more and haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten totally sick of it yet I began doing something like mentoring semi-regularly I&amp;rsquo;ve improved a lot at disconnecting from work I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to socialize occasionally through things like horror movie club, playing Among Us, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be aggressive, be be aggressive. But how aggressive?</title>
      <link>https://mrisdal.github.io/blog/posts/be-aggressive/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 19:47:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrisdal.github.io/blog/posts/be-aggressive/</guid>
      <description>This week I asked for feedback on something I wrote from a trusted colleague. My audience was larger than usual for me and 100% men (as far as I knew). Although I&amp;rsquo;m already pretty confident in my prose-writing skills, I felt greater than usual pressure to make a compelling, tight story. I wanted what I wrote to sound authoritative and well informed.
My colleague gave me great constructive feedback and overall really liked what I wrote.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Year in Review, 2019</title>
      <link>https://mrisdal.github.io/blog/posts/my-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 02:29:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrisdal.github.io/blog/posts/my-2019/</guid>
      <description>This is my own year-in-review. What started as a dumb tweet has become a blog post because I&amp;rsquo;m between jobs. Enjoy!
My 2019:
📽️ Film - Society (1989)
🎶 Song - Sandwich, Marco Minnemann (2016)
💽 Record - In the Court of the Crimson King (50th anniversary) King Crimson (2019)
📚 Book - Our Mathematical Universe, Max Tegmark (2014)
🎮 Game - Untitled Goose (2019)
🎙️ Podcast - SYSK (2008-2019)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Hobbies</title>
      <link>https://mrisdal.github.io/blog/posts/new-hobbies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 17:53:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrisdal.github.io/blog/posts/new-hobbies/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks ago I tweeted that I wanted to explore new hobbies. For the past couple of years, I&amp;rsquo;ve engrossed myself in a job I love. My career development has been really rewarding professionally, but lately I&amp;rsquo;ve felt personally underdeveloped. My current hobbies include seeing movies (especially horror and sci-fi) and exploring my new home of Los Angeles (biking, hiking, and of course eating). While these things are fun, I feel like I could be doing and creating so much more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://mrisdal.github.io/blog/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 15:51:11 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrisdal.github.io/blog/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Hello world! I&amp;rsquo;m recreating my personal website using Hugo. Previously it was written in Bootstrap. I hope you enjoy the new look and layout.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
