<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>communities on Meg Risdal</title>
    <link>https://www.meg.dev/tags/communities/</link>
    <description>Recent content in communities on Meg Risdal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>hello@meg.dev (Meg Risdal)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>hello@meg.dev (Meg Risdal)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 22:16:30 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.meg.dev/tags/communities/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Productive transparency in online communities: Inspiration from trains and IKEA</title>
      <link>https://www.meg.dev/posts/transparency-in-online-communities/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 22:16:30 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>hello@meg.dev (Meg Risdal)</author>
      <guid>https://www.meg.dev/posts/transparency-in-online-communities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Japanese train system is famously fast, clean, friendly, and efficient. On the drive home from my first day back at Google I was reminded of why as I listened to the &lt;em&gt;99% Invisible&lt;/em&gt; podcast episode &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://99percentinvisible.org/episode/wait-wait-tell-me/&#34;&gt;“Wait wait &amp;hellip; tell me!”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. I’ll give you the tl;dr summary of the story and explain some connections I made to product development for online communities that got me so in my head I missed my exit for the 405.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the secrets to Japan’s impressive system of bullet trains, called &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shinkansen&#34;&gt;Shinkansen&lt;/a&gt;, is simple. It’s the kind of elegant solution I dream of and representative of the values I hold as a product and community person. In order to improve rider satisfaction with wait times while trains were cleaned, the new CEO of Shinkansen didn&amp;rsquo;t sacrifice quality. Instead he introduced transparency between workers who cleaned trains and waiting customers. He did this by literally making workers more visible (e.g., bright red uniforms) instead of intentionally invisible (pale blue uniforms that blend in with their environs). Beyond physical appearances alone, he also encouraged workers to actually speak with passengers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making their work more visible in these ways had profound effects on behaviors in the system between workers and waiting passengers. Namely, passengers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Were less frustrated by wait times because they could better see and understand the purpose of waiting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Empathized with workers to the point of being more conscientious by proactively cleaning up their own messes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this transparency, passengers were empowered with insight into the common interests between themselves and workers. They not only tolerated the extra wait as workers cleaned trains, they embraced it. And no one had to tell them “because it’s good for you.” Additionally, Shinkansen was able to maintain high standards of cleanliness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a conversation with a friend about the Shinkansen train system story, he brought up IKEA’s cafeterias. The ones with the amazing Swedish meatballs and lingonberry sauce. Where you bus your own table. Not only is a DIY approach appropriate here (it’s IKEA!), they make it consistently transparent throughout the diner’s “user journey” so there’s no room for unmet expectations for Michelin-grade experiences. And it goes beyond signs everywhere. The carts where you stash your emptied trays are an unmissable centerpiece of the cafe. In most places they are hidden out of sight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1517816630506-a8c5ccf61bf0?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjEyMDd9&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=crop&amp;amp;w=1050&amp;amp;q=80&#34; alt=&#34;Blue and yellow IKEA building&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://unsplash.com/photos/KDawdoaC-ts&#34;&gt;Photo by Oleg Laptev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;https://mrisdal.github.io/blog/posts/reflections-on-stack-overflow/&#34;&gt;my blog post&lt;/a&gt; reflecting on my time leading product for Stack Overflow’s public Q&amp;amp;A, I alluded to tensions among different types of users. Curators and moderators and question-askers and question-answerers. One of the things that I think is well appreciated by moderators and curators (and probably many question-answerers, too) is the importance of the quality of content that gets created and maintained over time. Interestingly, question-askers (mostly new users) are the driving force behind content creation on Stack Overflow, yet often their local and immediate needs may not make the quality of the entire repository present in mind. The tension, in part, in my opinion is a lack of transparency between integral parts of the system (people!) that could be communicating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the flow a question enters when it&amp;rsquo;s closed was more transparent, would that help people understand why it happens? If people saw how content reviews help keep up a healthy ecosystem of question and answer pairs, would they more eagerly contribute to review themselves? What if the average user knew that without a small number of volunteer moderators handling flagged content toxicity would be double what it is?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve long thought that much of Kaggle’s relative welcomingness as an online technical community is its inherent temporal transparency between power users and newcomers. This started with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com/competitions&#34;&gt;Competitions&lt;/a&gt;. Each Competition which runs for a couple of months is a new shared objective for new and old users alike to collaborate and share ideas. Each competition generates a cohort that’s basically a community of practice with a deadline. Once it’s over, users often write-up their approaches (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com/c/ashrae-energy-prediction/discussion/124984&#34;&gt;example&lt;/a&gt;), sharing what they learned with the community. And then they start all over again with the next competition. Over time, each user is on a cycling trajectory from novice to expert and there’s always some new technique or framework to learn as the state of the art in machine learning evolves. I really believe it&amp;rsquo;s visibility and participation in constantly cycling cohorts with shared goals that make it easier for users of all levels to better empathize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an online community, you need to find ways to foster and incentivize ways to encourage different types of users to interact positively and contribute to your mission. I believe that transparency, especially by making shared goals and opportunities to empathize apparent in the product itself, can be an important way to achieve this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thank you once again to Josh Heyer (AKA Shog9) for his feedback on this post (and for talking to me about delicious lingonberry sauce). Thanks also to my fellow Kaggle Noobs moderators (Aakash, Yifan, Mikel, Jorge) for their discussion on this topic.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reply&#34;&gt;Reply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow the conversation and discuss on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;I wrote up some thoughts on transparency in online communities. 👀🤗 &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/b4rEd0VA2i&#34;&gt;https://t.co/b4rEd0VA2i&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; meg.ehh 🇨🇦 (@MeganRisdal) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MeganRisdal/status/1220193165535170560?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;January 23, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on Stack Overflow: Building Successful Communities</title>
      <link>https://www.meg.dev/posts/reflections-on-stack-overflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 00:48:59 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>hello@meg.dev (Meg Risdal)</author>
      <guid>https://www.meg.dev/posts/reflections-on-stack-overflow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is my last day at Stack Overflow. For most of this year, I was the lead product manager for their flagship product, public Q&amp;amp;A. In my last couple of weeks there, I spent some time reflecting on what I have learned and how my perspectives as a product leader matured. As someone deeply invested in building open developer communities, I continue to refine my opinions about how to approach building community-facing products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on these reflections, the following is my own personal perspective on what a product leader at a place like Stack Overflow can do to be successful (and hence make community products successful). Although they are pretty specific to Stack Overflow, I am taking what I’ve learned with me to my next endeavor and you may find them applicable to your world, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make Stack Overflow work for &lt;strong&gt;everyone&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be ambitious and a driver of positive change in the face of inertia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The community is an asset. Experiment, iterate, and listen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create simple defaults and tear down configuration and customization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep the mission and impact in perspective always.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;building-a-successful-community&#34;&gt;Building a successful community&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;make-stack-overflow-work-for-everyone-do-not-indulge-us-versus-them-dynamics&#34;&gt;Make Stack Overflow work for everyone. Do not indulge “us versus them” dynamics.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many types of people who use Stack Overflow. The main segments for Public Q&amp;amp;A are: Askers (including people who just look up answers to existing questions), Answerers, Curators, and Moderators. The interesting thing about Stack Overflow’s user base though is that all of these segments (of real people!) interact with each other in feedback loops:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People ask questions and other people answer those questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Curators identify quality issues and other people receive that feedback&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People flag content that doesn’t belong on the site and moderators handle those flags&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any initiatives that only serve one segment put the community and product into imbalance. In reality you’re making changes in a complex, dynamical system of real people in a community. Emphasizing one type of user also makes things unnecessarily personal. By “personal” I mean about people, not about the system/software. I observed that this triggers an “us versus them” backlash which is not necessary and causes users to suffer. Instead, focus on the system itself and how all different kinds of users participate in it to interact with each other. I believe that this is an approach that will inherently make Stack Overflow more welcoming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/dUf-m_ircDT_3QXoWEnrVqZqv6FFPSvBHz8UOmSYKT8l2S_R4SQQaaXK35XJKpa9cK1CLM_XCq7Stet6M2Xktq17Id94uK88sZs282LvXhJ2L0pJlBxEjApSujLK8QSzw6YUXZZZ&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some things I kept in mind when thinking about how to make Stack Overflow work for everyone:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Always ask “How does this impact users?”&lt;/em&gt;. In specs/briefs I write, I always explicitly consider all participants in the relevant feedback loop. Going through this motion can uncover unanswered questions, highlights your thought process for readers, develops a muscle for user-focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Treat everyone as a valuable person as part of the system&lt;/em&gt;. Even if I’m working on something mainly designed to help one type of user, it can go a LONG ways both internally and externally to demonstrate care for everyone. Other people will pick sides or favorites, but you as the chief advocate for your users cannot succumb to this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Think holistically&lt;/em&gt;. I tend to like to think of user journeys in product work. For a given feature, how did users arrive there? What’s the next step? Considering all participants at each touchpoint in a user journey is a natural extension of this thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;be-ambitious-and-a-driver-of-positive-change-in-the-face-of-inertia-exude-optimism&#34;&gt;Be ambitious and a driver of positive change in the face of inertia. Exude optimism.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team focused on public Q&amp;amp;A is shockingly small: four IC developers. And the surface area of responsibility is enormous: all of Stack Overflow and the Stack Exchange network serving millions of people every month. Stack Overflow is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.alexa.com/topsites&#34;&gt;top 50 site in Alexa rankings&lt;/a&gt;. Having the impact the user base needs and deserves requires efficient use of resources paired with a healthy openness to risk. Otherwise it’s too easy to slip into conservative bug-fixing mode to just keep the status quo afloat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news is that the team is super capable when pushed to dream big. When I joined in early 2019, we made 7 internal commitments of which only 28% were hit. In October, we made 31 internal commitments and hit an 84% completion. This was possible despite receiving no additional developer resources during this timeframe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some tips for keeping functional teams productive and engaged:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Constantly clarify ambiguities&lt;/em&gt;. The biggest thing a product manager can do to help team productivity is clarify ambiguities. In the face of chaos or shifting priorities, the best thing you can do is make sure to shield the team as much as possible so they can stay focused on productive project work. In the day to day, stay engaged with what they’re working on and answer their questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Accentuate the positive&lt;/em&gt;. This team has historically been subjected to a lot of strife. Be empathetic, but do your best to sincerely highlight successes and positive motivators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Connect the team with end users&lt;/em&gt;. Making the team clearly see how their work has impact is a morale boost and motivator. Some ways to do this include inviting developers to join user interviews, reviewing and discussing research with a broad group of people, and holding project retrospectives that include preliminary data on feature performance. In a small example, I always included a user quote in the team’s weekly company-wide report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-community-is-an-asset-experiment-iterate-and-listen-to-your-users-the-whole-time&#34;&gt;The community is an asset. Experiment, iterate, and listen to your users the whole time.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rapid experimentation, incremental releases, and iteration is an opportunity to keep a dialogue with your users open. It’s a venue for you to not only involve them in the conversation, but to shape it by sharing and aligning on goals. Like I once told a coworker, “We’re both on different vectors. I share mine with you and you share yours with me and we both get a little closer and amplify our efforts.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of examples of this approach took place as part of our bigger efforts to improve experiences related to question closing. In one recent project, we worked to &lt;a href=&#34;https://meta.stackexchange.com/questions/337013/new-post-notices-rollout-on-stack-overflow&#34;&gt;ship the new post notices feature early&lt;/a&gt; and we were responsive to feedback from users. This led to making lots of small improvements before &lt;a href=&#34;https://meta.stackexchange.com/questions/339700/new-post-notices-are-live-network-wide&#34;&gt;rolling the change out more broadly&lt;/a&gt;. In another example, we &lt;a href=&#34;https://meta.stackoverflow.com/questions/388313/experiment-ended-closing-and-reopening-happens-at-3-votes-for-the-next-30-day&#34;&gt;engaged the community closely&lt;/a&gt; in testing different thresholds for voting to close and reopen questions, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://meta.stackoverflow.com/questions/390083/threshold-experiment-results-closing-editing-and-reopening-all-become-more-eff&#34;&gt;transparently sharing&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/stackoverflow/experiment-results-testing-close-reopen-thresholds-on-stack-overflow-5a35&#34;&gt;results of our experiments&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/MAKHGYl_QDfLybaA-x6I5adBck2kCXvchwVJqWv319TBIrb9hibjlDOjO7aZ8s9UrKfsHWISpE10udrKDKQ2QQyBl20bv683P5neVj4umt5zpere-0uWfvqa8ljT9jJzOKAE1zK4&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stack Overflow is a website with a huge user base. Not taking advantage of the ability to run tests and get feedback from enthusiastic community members is a missed opportunity. Do it in complement with other research methods. At the same time, these feedback loops threaten to slow things down and can be emotionally draining. Your mileage may vary (and a lot seems to depend on individual tastes), but here are some quick tips:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Don’t take things personally&lt;/em&gt;. You’ll get a lot of critique, positive and negative. As a product manager you have to emotionally separate yourself from the features you work on as much as possible. Instead, invest your energy into focusing on the objectives you share with end users and other stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Delegate communication&lt;/em&gt;. It can be exhausting and extremely time consuming to interact deeply with a critical audience. Lean on people who are experts at this. For example, you can try strategies like ghostwriting blog posts or asking others to synthesize feedback for you in a report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Take a principled stance&lt;/em&gt;. Decision-making is easier when you already have clear objectives and guiding product principles to use as heuristics. So form these early and lean on them aggressively to quickly resolve feedback rather than debating minutiae at length.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where appropriate, experimenting and iterating on ideas in public is also a great way to battle harden new features before introducing them to Teams customers, &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/teams&#34;&gt;Stack Overflow’s Private Q&amp;amp;A product&lt;/a&gt;. If something is successful at Stack Overflow’s scale, it may work for a company’s internal knowledge management, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;create-simple-defaults-and-tear-down-configuration-and-customization-do-not-try-to-please-everyone&#34;&gt;Create simple defaults and tear down configuration and customization. Do not try to please everyone.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stack Overflow is too complex. It’s hard to use for people who are not power users, it’s difficult to maintain for engineers, and it’s a challenge to design and build changes that work around tons of variants. This is not sustainable for such a small team with a huge mandate. For example, take &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/users/8157789/megan-risdal?tab=profile&#34;&gt;user profiles&lt;/a&gt;. They’re a mess of information overload, they’re bogged down with tons of settings and togglable preferences (some only used by a tiny number of people), and users can maintain unique profiles for each and every network site that they’re a member of. Then there’s the overall network profile. And chat profiles. Then profiles for Teams (private Q&amp;amp;A), too. Oh, and they’re not mobile responsive. Yuck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/MIAbOqg_Uccnlufi4Ubuos2FTc1fCe-1r1ZF2XUHu3eknZnGiN_Xg6B5WJMkp8RW54ILnF1V0WveZJgiNlVDXrWKnE-bPUnmvomfIUwzoNoiQXk0Kh3rlb7QGUfgjL8K9YB2Nizw&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking things away by simplifying them will be hard, but it’s necessary for the future of Stack Overflow. When I first joined Stack Overflow in March, the team launched the new &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.blog/2019/08/22/impact-of-ask-question-wizard/&#34;&gt;Ask Question Wizard&lt;/a&gt;. This created a whole new default question-asking flow for users with less than 111 reputation while other users had the old (10 years old) form intact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UX of the wizard was clunky. We heard this in feedback from a random sample of people who responded to our new monthly site satisfaction survey. And maintaining it AND the existing form was an immediate timesuck as we battled bugs and strange edge cases arising from technical workarounds required to support this complex feature. It wouldn’t surprise me if its measurable benefits actually stemmed from how hard it was to use. Therefore, we went back to the drawing board, taking what we learned from the wizard &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.blog/2019/09/26/research-update-improving-the-question-asking-experience/&#34;&gt;plus additional research&lt;/a&gt;, and launched a redesign of the question-asking form for everyone. The data (&lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.blog/2019/11/12/research-update-a-b-testing-the-new-question-form/&#34;&gt;quantitative&lt;/a&gt; and qualitative) and increased simplicity led us to consider it a huge improvement. Plus, it’s now way easier to iterate on (since of course it’s still not perfect!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do more to reduce forking paths and little used customizations. It’s not realistic to continue supporting these given extremely constrained resources and minimal benefit to users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This web of time – the strands of which approach one another, bifurcate, intersect or ignore each other through the centuries – embraces every possibility. We do not exist in most of them. In some you exist and not I, while in others I do, and you do not.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;― Jorge Luis Borges, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/work/quotes/14566729&#34;&gt;The Garden of Forking Paths&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some tips for approaching this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Make data-driven decisions&lt;/em&gt;. Use data (quantitative and qualitative) at every level to inform how you solve this problem. Use data to prioritize which things to tackle first and then use data to decide what configurations are most important, for instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Involve all stakeholders in decision-making&lt;/em&gt;. You really, really have to know who is dependent on something and how when you’re planning to take it away. Make sure to involve the right people in the conversation and, as much as possible, share the same data you have access to (and invite them to ask new questions, too).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have empathy&lt;/em&gt;. Loss aversion is a very real thing. Even if simplifying something is the best thing for users by all other accounts, taking something away still hurts. And this impacts not just end users, but the people who originally worked on a feature. You can have empathy by understanding how they use the feature and asking about the historical context around its original creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;keep-the-mission-and-impact-in-perspective-always&#34;&gt;Keep the mission and impact in perspective always.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With respect to mission, a lot of people are passionate about Stack Overflow and its community. There are a lot of loud voices and strong opinions pulling in many directions. Do what you can to keep focus on the bigger picture, both inside the team and externally. In this period of transition for the company, the mission is still being honed, but here are some things I personally believe to be important:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stack Overflow is a source of high quality question and answer pairs&lt;/strong&gt;. Do things that continue to grow this content, enrich it, and make it easier to access and use for all developers. But, Stack Overflow is not equivalent to Wikipedia. It’s not made up of facts frozen in time. More than a traditional encyclopedia, relevant information and practices in Stack Overflow’s community change as the developer landscape evolves. Make Stack Overflow a living, evolving library. It will never be “done”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make Stack Overflow for all developers&lt;/strong&gt;. It started as a place to serve programming enthusiasts and this was a successful way to catalyze the creation of a community and corpus of technical knowledge. Over time, it has clearly shown potential to make lives better for anyone who writes code. Figure out how to make Stack Overflow a place where anyone in the world who codes has a place to participate and learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With respect to impact, this is where it’s all too easy to fall into a trap of listening only to a small minority of people who enthusiastically offer their voices. These voices are super important to be sure, but they need to be balanced. In my time at Stack Overflow, we put a lot of effort into filling gaps in who we listened to. The vast majority of people who use Stack Overflow don’t have accounts (or aren’t logged-in) yet we had virtually no way to hear from them until we launched a &lt;a href=&#34;https://static.googleusercontent.com/media/research.google.com/en//pubs/archive/43221.pdf&#34;&gt;satisfaction tracking survey&lt;/a&gt; last summer. At the same time, we also strengthened ties between Community Management and product as a way to more scalably incorporate feedback from highly engaged users into the work we prioritized. They need to have a seat at the table in all of major feature work in order to continue to have a big impact on the solutions the team designs. They are experts on different types of user segments as well as the system and are critical to building Stack Overflow to better serve everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continue keeping impact in perspective and strive to better serve the needs of all types of users. It’s difficult, painful work because limited resources means important people may feel ignored. But I have confidence that progress will continue to be made on this front.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-conclusion&#34;&gt;In conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These beliefs are a reflection of my own personal values as a growing product leader who’s passionate about building great experiences for global developer communities, and as someone who has a great deal of optimism about the future of Stack Overflow. If I had to sum them up, I’d say I believe in unrelenting user focus and optimizing for global, rather than local, minima. I’m excited to take these values, along with everything I learned at Stack Overflow, with me in my next adventure: rejoining the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com/&#34;&gt;Kaggle&lt;/a&gt; team at Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thank you to Shog9, Donna Choi, and Julia Silge for their feedback on drafts of this post.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reply&#34;&gt;Reply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow the conversation and discuss on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Read my reflections on Stack Overflow and how my product thinking around building for communities has matured &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/FCKEXDlLKi&#34;&gt;https://t.co/FCKEXDlLKi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; meg.ehh 🇨🇦 (@MeganRisdal) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MeganRisdal/status/1203000660817367041?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;December 6, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Interview with Superlinguo: Linguists in Careers</title>
      <link>https://www.meg.dev/posts/superlinguo-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 00:29:18 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>hello@meg.dev (Meg Risdal)</author>
      <guid>https://www.meg.dev/posts/superlinguo-interview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.superlinguo.com/post/188176778397/linguistics-jobs-interview-with-a-product-manager&#34;&gt;cross-posted from an interview I recently did with Superlinguo&lt;/a&gt;, a language and linguistics blog by Lauren Gawne, for her excellent linguists in careers series.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Lauren:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of tech people I know say “the best skill a programmer can have is knowing how to look up the right answer on Stack Exchange” It’s one of those websites that people use every day, but perhaps without thinking about how it gets built. Megan Risdal is one of the people who make Stack Overflow happen, as a Product Manager leading Public Q&amp;amp;A. As Megan mentions below, there’s even a &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguistics.stackexchange.com/&#34;&gt;Linguistics Stack Exchange&lt;/a&gt; (you might just see some old &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguistics.stackexchange.com/users/64/laureng&#34;&gt;answers from me&lt;/a&gt; there). Megan has not only forged a career for herself in tech, she helps demystify the industry for other linguists who might follow in her footsteps, on Twitter (@MeganRisdal) and her &lt;a href=&#34;meg.dev&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://66.media.tumblr.com/05270b919fb9c719ff5cd491b37cbc67/16001c6a0b1b48e1-83/s500x750/b18e006454ce10d5d11c582767ff40371240094d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-did-you-study-at-university&#34;&gt;What did you study at university?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My undergraduate degree is in Psychology from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uwec.edu/&#34;&gt;University of Wisconsin, Eau Claire&lt;/a&gt; where my interests were in &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Differential_psychology&#34;&gt;individual differences&lt;/a&gt;. I also did a minor in French and this is where I first learned about linguistics as a field of study. My combined interests in language and individual differences psychology led me to completing a senior thesis project on variation in attitudes towards linguistic diversity. Just last year this work was published with my then advisor, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uwec.edu/profiles/bensonej/&#34;&gt;Dr. Erica Benson&lt;/a&gt;, as a chapter in &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cambridge.org/us/academic/subjects/languages-linguistics/sociolinguistics/language-regard-methods-variation-and-change?format=HB&#34;&gt;Language Regard: Methods, Variation, and Change&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From here, I did a Master’s degree in Sociolinguistics at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncsu.edu/&#34;&gt;North Carolina State University&lt;/a&gt;. Building on my statistics background from studying psychology, I dove deeper into quantitative methods, learning R along the way, while focusing on sociophonetics and laboratory phonology. For my capstone project, I measured articulatory (ultrasound tongue imaging), aerodynamic, (nasal/oral airflow), and acoustic variation in coarticulatory vowel nasalization strategies among Anglo-American and African American (Vernacular) English speakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I started a PhD at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ucla.edu/&#34;&gt;UCLA&lt;/a&gt; where I intended to continue studying laboratory phonology. I only ended up finishing one year which was spent on theoretical foundations, articulatory phonetics, and learnability before leaving with a second Master’s degree in Linguistics. I ended up deciding to leave academia because I was disillusioned already with the prospect of the job market and the limited potential for my work to have impact beyond academia. I made my mind up when I applied for a job at Google and got an interview. I ultimately failed, but this was enough for me to feel confident my resume was “good enough” (completely incidentally I ended up later getting hired and working at Google for a couple of years prior to my current role).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-your-job&#34;&gt;What is your job?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past six months I’ve been working as a Product Manager at &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/&#34;&gt;Stack Overflow&lt;/a&gt; where I lead the team working on public Q&amp;amp;A. If you’re not familiar with Stack Overflow, it’s a site where anyone who codes can come to find answers to their programming questions. We also have the Stack Exchange network which has similar Q&amp;amp;A sites for other topics like cooking and anime. There’s even a &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguistics.stackexchange.com/&#34;&gt;Linguistics Stack Exchange&lt;/a&gt; site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my day-to-day, as a product manager, I work closely with our developers, designers, researchers, data scientists, community managers, marketing, and leadership. So, it’s a lot of meetings and a lot of Google Docs. My job entails taking many, many inputs and synthesizing them into a strategy and product roadmap that the team executes on to make Stack Overflow a more useful, engaging place for all developers. On a given day, you could catch me writing a new feature specification for a developer, reviewing results of an experiment with our data scientists, or dropping in on user interviews. One of the things I love the most about my job is the variety. If a project is slipping or we just don’t have the resources for something important, I’m the person who can step in and do what it takes to make sure the work of my collaborators adds up to something successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-does-your-linguistics-training-help-you-in-your-job&#34;&gt;How does your linguistics training help you in your job?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My training in linguistics absolutely helps me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, and most importantly I believe, my background in sociolinguistics has taught me the significance of diversity among groups of people (like users of a product) in so many ways. For example, Stack Overflow sees many millions of users every month, but we know that not everyone is equally likely to participate on the site. There are huge, intimidating barriers to participation which disproportionately impact different groups of people depending on things like their background and experience coding. So every day I think about how changes to the product will affect different types of users. Me and my team are constantly striving to better understand the important ways our users vary in their backgrounds, motivations, and pain points and how we can better meet their needs. Especially in a globally diverse online community like ours where users interact and community with each other it’s extremely important for me and my colleagues to think about always.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, and more concretely, the quantitative methods and experimental best practices I acquired while studying linguistics are highly applicable to my day-to-day job. We make use of a lot of different qualitative and quantitative research methods at Stack Overflow and having training in this area allows me to leverage these resources effectively in my product decision-making. Before I joined Stack Overflow, I had also spent some time as a data scientist, so my background in statistics and R was extremely relevant there. Without this training, I don’t think I would be where I am today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;do-you-have-any-advice-do-you-wish-someone-had-given-to-you-about-linguisticscareersuniversity&#34;&gt;Do you have any advice do you wish someone had given to you about linguistics/careers/university?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I’m very happy with my trajectory. I’m extremely grateful to everyone who supported me at every stage and I would not be where I am today without all of these experience (yes including dropping out of a PhD!). That said, some thing that I wish I had encountered sooner are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seriously, build a public portfolio. Make your work visible. Curate an online presence. Having even a just a modest &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MeganRisdal&#34;&gt;Twitter following&lt;/a&gt; and some publicly discoverable content with my name on it has helped me immeasurably in my career. Oh, and learn git.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pay &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; attention to what’s going on outside of your academic bubble. I fully intended to stay in academia when I started my PhD at UCLA. Had I thought somewhat ahead of time about the possibility that I would end up industry, I may have prioritized different classes or perhaps even chosen a different PhD program altogether. For example, if you have a choice between learning OCaml and Python, maybe see what non-academia has to say, too, as an input to your decision. Then again, hindsight is 2020. I would have seriously regretted not taking statistics/research methods under any circumstances, though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;any-other-thoughts-or-comments&#34;&gt;Any other thoughts or comments?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think every tech company should look to hire people trained in linguistics. There are so, so many ways in which a background in linguistics is relevant to so many careers in tech. From user research to data science to (apparently) product management, a background in linguistics adds a unique and valuable perspective. If you’re not sure what you’re qualified for, carefully tailor your experience, cast your net wide, and seek out advice!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more interviews on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.superlinguo.com/&#34;&gt;Superlinguo&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reply&#34;&gt;Reply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow the conversation and discuss on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;My Interview with &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/superlinguo?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@superlinguo&lt;/a&gt;: Linguists in Careers &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/crosspost?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#crosspost&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/BVO9nK3v84&#34;&gt;https://t.co/BVO9nK3v84&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; meg.ehh 🇨🇦 (@MeganRisdal) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MeganRisdal/status/1202825630632439809?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;December 6, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Know Nothing</title>
      <link>https://www.meg.dev/posts/how-to-know-nothing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 17:00:27 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>hello@meg.dev (Meg Risdal)</author>
      <guid>https://www.meg.dev/posts/how-to-know-nothing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of months ago I started a new job as a product manager at Stack Overflow. This blog post is about how to know nothing in a new job. It&amp;rsquo;s about that whiplash-like experience of going from confidently knowing everything there is to know about your work to coming to a grinding to halt so you can start all over again from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://frinkiac.com/video/S09E19/TZFO4rsFaIkVsYcDt05xmH3LkhE=.gif&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, maybe it&amp;rsquo;s not so dramatic as that, but the insecure feelings I was having inspired me to ask for advice from my Twitter followers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Going from knowing everything and a half at one job to starting fresh is rough. Anyone have any tips for feeling better about it?&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; meg.ehh 🇨🇦 (@MeganRisdal) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MeganRisdal/status/1120880418562002945?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;April 24, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To give some more background, I was feeling especially daunted by my own lack of knowledge for a couple of reasons, I think:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com/mrisdal&#34;&gt;Kaggle&lt;/a&gt; (my previous job) I worked through a really exciting high growth period. When I started in 2016, they were focused mainly on competitions and towards the end of my time there we had massively expanded the community, the product, and the team. We even lived through a successful acquisition by Google. I was present as a participant, either as a &amp;ldquo;witness&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;creator&amp;rdquo;, in all of this change. I felt that I could competently answer just about any question someone (internal or external) could ask me about Kaggle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, the company I&amp;rsquo;ve joined (&lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/users/8157789/megan-risdal?tab=profile&#34;&gt;Stack Overflow&lt;/a&gt;) is quite a bit like Kaggle in that it has a large, technical userbase with a rich history of cultural norms and past product decisions. That rich history has made Stack Overflow the household brand it is today, but it can feel intimidating as someone who wasn&amp;rsquo;t an active participant in it over the years. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot of tribal knowledge to catch up on!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, for this blog post I wanted to summarize some of the great advice I got from folks on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-its-normal-and-okay-to-feel-insecure&#34;&gt;1. It&amp;rsquo;s normal and okay to feel insecure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is worth mentioning up front! I got a number of replies from people either expressing solidarity or assuring me it&amp;rsquo;s a normal feeling for anyone starting a new job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Any time one starts a new job, it is completely normal to feel overwhelmed and insecure about your knowledge. Remember, starting out fresh is overwhelming for anyone. It&amp;#39;s completely normal for people to take 60-90 days to get up to speed.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Just remember you are kickass!&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; JSON Baumgartner (@jasonbaumgartne) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jasonbaumgartne/status/1121099345535864842?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;April 24, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-remind-yourself-you-were-competent-and-you-will-be-again&#34;&gt;2. Remind yourself you were competent and you will be again&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is for those of us that laugh at the idea of ever succumbing to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dunning%E2%80%93Kruger_effect&#34;&gt;Dunning–Kruger effect&lt;/a&gt; when it comes to evaluating our own competence. I&amp;rsquo;ll admit that I requested my personnel file when leaving Google so I have my performance reviews to remind me that I &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; kick ass at my job in some objective-ish sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like this reply from someone else who recently changed teams:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;I mean j still feel hella dumb.. but I know I feel dumb because I&amp;#39;m learning new things. Which helps me realize I&amp;#39;m not really dumb. It&amp;#39;s just how I feel.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Fred v3.0.0 🤖🎸 (@ProbNotABot) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ProbNotABot/status/1121188776250888192?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;April 24, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-lean-into-your-newbie-perspective-as-superpower&#34;&gt;3. Lean into your newbie perspective as superpower&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was probably my favorite reply (from a former colleague at Google):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;It helps when people remind me that being new to a company/role/tech area is a super power. You have fresh eyes, new perspectives, ideas for connections not yet made.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Keep wearing those newbie cuffs of power as long as you can!&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; commandasaurus 🦖 (@amcasari) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/amcasari/status/1120881183552757760?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;April 24, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was also stated nicely by another person who &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ztuylime/status/1121132899166605312&#34;&gt;replied with this quote&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the beginner&amp;rsquo;s mind there are many possibilities,
but in the expert&amp;rsquo;s there are few
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dailyzen.com/journal/zen-mind-beginners-mind&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shunryu Suzuki&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because I know I have a lot to learn in my new role, I&amp;rsquo;ve had an amazing opportunity to ask &amp;ldquo;Why?&amp;rdquo; so many times. I&amp;rsquo;m definitely going to keep wearing this hat for as long as I can as I talk to both coworkers &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MeganRisdal/status/1127006719492509701?s=20&#34;&gt;as well as users&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/aCraigPfeifer/status/1121089455538999297&#34;&gt;As someone else replied&lt;/a&gt;, by challenging assumptions you&amp;rsquo;re &amp;ldquo;both learning about the environment and moving it forward.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-be-vulnerable&#34;&gt;4. Be vulnerable&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People can only help you if they know what you&amp;rsquo;re struggling with or how you want to improve. Maybe it wasn&amp;rsquo;t comfortable for me to tweet the world about not knowing everything, but it got me some amazing replies that can hopefully help even more people than just myself. Plus, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/richwag/status/1120907365157625856&#34;&gt;as someone replied&lt;/a&gt;, &amp;ldquo;If you don&amp;rsquo;t feel uncomfortable you&amp;rsquo;re not learning.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;I dunno, I&amp;#39;ve really struggled to have this kind of vulnerability in my new gig and I think I&amp;#39;ve come off as a know-it-all asshole at times. I think you&amp;#39;re winning 😁&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Justin Kiggins (@neuromusic) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/neuromusic/status/1120915698350321664?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;April 24, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This also ties in well with &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/tinkertim/status/1120887904287494145&#34;&gt;some other advice I got&lt;/a&gt; to request feedback early and often as a newcomer to a team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve distilled the advice I got into the several different themes I wrote about above, but at the end of the day my two biggest takeaways are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be patient with yourself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be inquisitive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And eventually you &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; know something again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reply&#34;&gt;Reply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow the conversation and discuss on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;How to know nothing &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/awlln2Y3b7&#34;&gt;https://t.co/awlln2Y3b7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; meg.ehh 🇨🇦 (@MeganRisdal) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MeganRisdal/status/1127699988551626752?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;May 12, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>