<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>career on Meg Risdal</title>
    <link>https://www.meg.dev/categories/career/</link>
    <description>Recent content in career on Meg Risdal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>hello@meg.dev (Meg Risdal)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>hello@meg.dev (Meg Risdal)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 18:47:03 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.meg.dev/categories/career/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Product management lessons learned through King Crimson lyrics</title>
      <link>https://www.meg.dev/posts/king-crimson-lyrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 18:47:03 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>hello@meg.dev (Meg Risdal)</author>
      <guid>https://www.meg.dev/posts/king-crimson-lyrics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Almost every musician I listen to carries influences of the progressive rock band King Crimson. For instance, my favorite musician Steven Wilson has put out entire albums that (to me) sounds like a King Crimson “project”. Including his debut solo album &lt;em&gt;Grace for Drowning&lt;/em&gt; which featured several King Crimson members including Tony Levin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I realized not only does King Crimson&amp;rsquo;s sound echo prodigiously within the discographies of my favorite artists, they&amp;rsquo;ve also had a thing or two to say about good (and bad) product management over the decades!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without further ado, I present: product management lessons learned through King Crimson lyrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;epitaph&#34;&gt;Epitaph&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-C-HytsGYg0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowledge is a deadly friend&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If no one sets the rules&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fate of all mankind, I see&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is in the hands of fools&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great power comes from great responsibility and your team looks to you to set the rules. If they sense they’re in the hands of fools, well, confusion will be their epitaph … it’s important to set a strong vision and get buy-in!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;three-of-a-perfect-pair&#34;&gt;Three of a Perfect Pair&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kKkGMA5gcC0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She is susceptible&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is impossible&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They have their cross to share&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three of a perfect pair&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He has his contradicting views&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She has her cyclothymic moods&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They make a study in despair&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three of a perfect pair&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This song is clearly about channeling healthy conflict within “The Triad”: engineering, design, and PM. If things get complicated, aggravated, you’ll end up with a perfect mess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;starless&#34;&gt;Starless&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/FhKJgqxNDD8&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sundown dazzling day&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gold through my eyes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But my eyes turned within&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only see&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starless and bible black&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there’s any reason why product managers exist, it’s to set a direction and chart a path for their team to get there. Without a north star, your smiles will only signal emptiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;frame-by-frame&#34;&gt;Frame by Frame&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OxfSC9GybPA&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frame by frame (Suddenly)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Death by drowning (from within)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your, in your analysis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Product managers are constantly making and facilitating decisions. Speed and quality count. Breaking things down step by step can help ensure you don’t fall prey to analysis paralysis so you can keep your team unblocked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dinosaur&#34;&gt;Dinosaur&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZyBqpjcissc&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ignorance has alway been something I excel in&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Followed by naivety and pride&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doesn&amp;rsquo;t take a scientist to see how&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any clever predator could have a piece of me&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike the fossil in these lyrics, a product manager should reflect and learn from their mistakes. For that matter, a good product manager is &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; eager to learn and innovate. Otherwise someone will be digging your bones, too …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reply&#34;&gt;Reply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow the conversation and discuss on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Have you wanted to learn some product management lessons via King Crimson lyrics? I got you. &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/jYqFGLAyng&#34;&gt;https://t.co/jYqFGLAyng&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; meg.ehh 🇨🇦 (@MeganRisdal) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MeganRisdal/status/1319822484754042880?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;October 24, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making public mistakes &amp; code memes: The origin of my famous Titanic notebook</title>
      <link>https://www.meg.dev/posts/my-titanic-notebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 13:38:46 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>hello@meg.dev (Meg Risdal)</author>
      <guid>https://www.meg.dev/posts/my-titanic-notebook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, it was a great honor to be a guest on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/nickwan&#34;&gt;Nick Wan&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; data science livestream on Twitch to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitch.tv/videos/720567732?t=00h20m40s&#34;&gt;talk through bad (and less bad) data viz that I&amp;rsquo;ve created&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- In case I can get this working later
&lt;iframe
    src=&#34;https://player.twitch.tv/?video=v720567732&amp;time=00h20m40s&#34;
    height=&#34;300&#34;
    width=&#34;400&#34;
    frameborder=&#34;0&#34;
    scrolling=&#34;no&#34;
    allowfullscreen=&#34;false&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a lot of fun! Talking about the history of my popular Titanic R notebook on Kaggle was a great opportunity for me to reflect on my data science journey. Its explosive success was very unintended. But as a result I&amp;rsquo;ve got a couple of cool insights to share about this experience and how I apply them in my role as a product manager at Kaggle today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-history&#34;&gt;The history&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven&amp;rsquo;t come across my introductory ML tutorial on the Titanic Getting Started Competition, then I guess I can&amp;rsquo;t count you among the over half million views it&amp;rsquo;s received in the past 4+ years. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com/mrisdal/exploring-survival-on-the-titanic&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Exploring Survival on the Titanic&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; was my very first public notebook on Kaggle. According to the notebook&amp;rsquo;s history, I created it in March 2016. And the story behind it is perhaps semi-interesting!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flashback to late 2015, I had recently joined Kaggle as a user. After mastering out of my PhD in linguistics and getting my first job doing data science for market research, I was hoping to tap into and learn from the machine learning community. While I was waiting for Kaggle to launch a good tabular dataset competition to dip my toes into (still waiting &amp;hellip;), I was mostly playing around with their newly launched public datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few months later, Kaggle&amp;rsquo;s newsletter landed in my inbox. They were hiring a part-time content marketing intern. Yes! This could be perfect for me. As the only data scientist at my job, I was eager to make connections and learn in this field. So an opportunity to create content, get feedback, and interview top data scientists was a dream. I applied and after doing an interview and submitting a writing sample, I was asked to do a short test project creating a tutorial notebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This short project ended up becoming the legendary Titanic notebook! In addition to receiving (at time of writing) 542,816 views, it&amp;rsquo;s been upvoted 3,388 times, forked 6,135 times, and has almost 1,000 comments. I never imagined my work test would become one of the top pieces of content on the platform, even 4+ years later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lessons-learned&#34;&gt;Lessons learned&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;imperfections-reborn-as-blessings&#34;&gt;Imperfections reborn as blessings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my interview with Nick, we focused mostly on the bad data viz aspects of my notebook. I explained that the time constraints of the short job test forced me to focus on the aspects which I considered most important:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delivering an end-to-end tutorial&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A technical yet fun narrative that showed off my writing skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I definitely didn&amp;rsquo;t focus on the quality of the data visualizations in the couple of hours I spent on this notebook. Instead, once I got one part working, I moved on to the next. In some places, I wanted to test what was possible in this new-to-me platform which leads to some unusual choices in retrospect which gave us plenty to talk about (what was I thinking with that mosaic plot?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.kaggleusercontent.com/kf/2020416/eyJhbGciOiJkaXIiLCJlbmMiOiJBMTI4Q0JDLUhTMjU2In0..7O_SLGfRoS5-KMTnn7m1Gg.TzoJE1yl45bOs1NUIWjrLDScObr1oa4TzMVCkRCgjem3WZDCYGuH9UjCTDSlKF4h270qrX_23Gc9u8LtRtUmfj30gg1PYE4cefcnT8o3WMc_ioQOuOKa8gAXumqgNypgD_VgDW6Lkifbt89thT_C9lDAxzgA7Gdnmz_quoh3ikWeKR6nFL77UYWruoiMbGXdhKGzG2RxaNWEx0C1dNZbDChh0JDR_5LWpUteLSEvuSBpTn5twMGBU8iMddALf7r0KOa49iQk29u5s3BcTElRZfTSkda8yJLmQIg8strYj54kONVCReqZkzo4NsjrZi7Ravo9KAON86eB8MQ_Ic8NUpiJOZ5XxnpBRznRk-7dQ2ESv8T54VmYh4HftGdHIRd3C6jJUeKbJ74CVE6Rupu9RqFsbV_uBcFKVvaCRNV4G1dGWzg2eOu2UOedlfoL6-3yB4louD3LnYE8_MZDVyOdF2TW7DGNiM8n0qX15ZuVlVmBLKAyyg8AyC6zW8TxXG4iHvU2GaEFGMDk970T09xVZcidIGvEYk1Ey7TnBQowLnQqL8IgVnE8DVrN1tfjJfXQEz_ZbrtTXMPjJ0t6r4h4wKoVNO7bgwvoDMFEGU7lU0H2rgEFqkypI6PZ0hHTBHbvLNIo-GZcbhyUO6lz7fnntQ.LTbN0FfZK44JvhmQM0TTqA/__results___files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-7-1.png&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;I can make a mosaic plot! But why?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, I&amp;rsquo;m glad I focused on writing over data visualization or even quality of my code (because this is what I was evaluated on and I got the job, after all). Now that the notebook has seen such success with newcomers to machine learning, I think its flaws are actually a good thing in two ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, as you might be able to glean from the comments if you read them, it&amp;rsquo;s very easy to find areas to improve upon my work. This makes this notebook a great launching pad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, if you can improve upon something that&amp;rsquo;s as popular as my Titanic notebook, hopefully that gives you a (well deserved) confidence boost as a learner! These kinds of wins are really motivating early on and to the extent this notebook as enabled that feeling for many people, I&amp;rsquo;m really proud of it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all of this, I experienced how much you stand to learn from the community when you put yourself out there early and often even if it requires knowingly making mistakes in public. Today, as a product manager at Kaggle, this reinforces for me how important it is for Kaggle&amp;rsquo;s community to be open to people from all over the world who are putting themselves out there to ask questions and learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;code-snippets-as-memes&#34;&gt;Code snippets as memes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another observation that I shared in my interview with Nick was about how I&amp;rsquo;d see other people copy distinctive bits of my data visualization code in their notebooks. I&amp;rsquo;d notice my plots repurposed for different datasets in my Kaggle newsfeed or just browsing others&amp;rsquo; notebooks. Since I&amp;rsquo;m not particularly enamored with my own data viz work here, it was kind of embarrassing to see my mistakes proliferate!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.kaggleusercontent.com/kf/2020416/eyJhbGciOiJkaXIiLCJlbmMiOiJBMTI4Q0JDLUhTMjU2In0..7O_SLGfRoS5-KMTnn7m1Gg.TzoJE1yl45bOs1NUIWjrLDScObr1oa4TzMVCkRCgjem3WZDCYGuH9UjCTDSlKF4h270qrX_23Gc9u8LtRtUmfj30gg1PYE4cefcnT8o3WMc_ioQOuOKa8gAXumqgNypgD_VgDW6Lkifbt89thT_C9lDAxzgA7Gdnmz_quoh3ikWeKR6nFL77UYWruoiMbGXdhKGzG2RxaNWEx0C1dNZbDChh0JDR_5LWpUteLSEvuSBpTn5twMGBU8iMddALf7r0KOa49iQk29u5s3BcTElRZfTSkda8yJLmQIg8strYj54kONVCReqZkzo4NsjrZi7Ravo9KAON86eB8MQ_Ic8NUpiJOZ5XxnpBRznRk-7dQ2ESv8T54VmYh4HftGdHIRd3C6jJUeKbJ74CVE6Rupu9RqFsbV_uBcFKVvaCRNV4G1dGWzg2eOu2UOedlfoL6-3yB4louD3LnYE8_MZDVyOdF2TW7DGNiM8n0qX15ZuVlVmBLKAyyg8AyC6zW8TxXG4iHvU2GaEFGMDk970T09xVZcidIGvEYk1Ey7TnBQowLnQqL8IgVnE8DVrN1tfjJfXQEz_ZbrtTXMPjJ0t6r4h4wKoVNO7bgwvoDMFEGU7lU0H2rgEFqkypI6PZ0hHTBHbvLNIo-GZcbhyUO6lz7fnntQ.LTbN0FfZK44JvhmQM0TTqA/__results___files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-11-1.png&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A strobe light in boxplot form, complete with hardcoded values.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code snippets are kind of like chunks of genetic material. Probably stuff that tends to work pretty well will replicate successfully in an ecosystem. And my notebook had a lot of signals of being a &amp;ldquo;good idea&amp;rdquo; in general: lots of views and upvotes, lots of forks, lots of comments, and highish score on the competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, I&amp;rsquo;d argue that publicly sharing and reusing reproducible code under an open license has been a good thing for developer productivity. But there are plenty of traps, too, as I witnessed my own flawed code go viral like it was some meme. This is something that I think a lot about now in my capacity as a product manager for Kaggle Notebooks (and as someone who previously worked at Stack Overflow). Questions like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What signals do you use to know some code you&amp;rsquo;re looking at is high quality and trustworthy?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can we make it easier to find and effectively reuse useful, high quality code snippets?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do you safely and easily update code snippets (mine are over four years old and probably still circulating)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Especially if you have thoughts about how to measure quality, I&amp;rsquo;m interested in chatting more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to my willingness to publish what you could call &amp;ldquo;bad data viz&amp;rdquo; today, I&amp;rsquo;ve come a really long ways in my career. It&amp;rsquo;s been an awesome journey from doing a small work test in a notebook to now managing that very notebook product in a few years. In a fun twist of fate, I suppose now I&amp;rsquo;m even responsible for how slowly this page loads due to its popularity!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to hear more about my journey and my perspectives on data visualization (including an example of a &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; data viz), check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitch.tv/videos/720567732?t=00h20m40s&#34;&gt;my interview on Nick Wan&amp;rsquo;s Twitch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reply&#34;&gt;Reply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow the conversation and discuss on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Making public mistakes &amp;amp; code memes: The origin of my famous Titanic notebook 🚢 &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/4WzqYRLly9&#34;&gt;https://t.co/4WzqYRLly9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; meg.ehh 🇨🇦 (@MeganRisdal) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MeganRisdal/status/1298398384529633280?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;August 25, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be aggressive, be be aggressive. But how aggressive?</title>
      <link>https://www.meg.dev/posts/be-aggressive/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 19:47:01 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>hello@meg.dev (Meg Risdal)</author>
      <guid>https://www.meg.dev/posts/be-aggressive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week I asked for feedback on something I wrote from a trusted colleague. My audience was larger than usual for me and 100% men (as far as I knew). Although I&amp;rsquo;m already pretty confident in my prose-writing skills, I felt greater than usual pressure to make a compelling, tight story. I wanted what I wrote to sound authoritative and well informed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My colleague gave me great constructive feedback and overall really liked what I wrote. Except one spot where I came across as harsh and somewhat arrogant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cringed. &lt;em&gt;I know, I know&lt;/em&gt;. When drafting that particular point, I had literally thought to myself (knowing that I can tend to hedge too much) &amp;ldquo;Okay, try to sound very assertive and &lt;em&gt;masculine&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;rdquo; It wasn&amp;rsquo;t me. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t my style or my voice. And it ended up sounding too abrasive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, easy enough fix. I softened the language and sent it off to my co-authors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, I kept thinking about this. It really made me realize how I&amp;rsquo;m constantly monitoring how I speak and write to perfectly balance cold authority and warm personability. Whether I&amp;rsquo;m self conscious about the number of &amp;ldquo;:)&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;!&amp;rdquo; that I use in an email or my willingness to admit &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know&amp;rdquo; in a meeting, it&amp;rsquo;s a perpetual struggle against my natural tendencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing is, I rarely actually feel 100% confident. But I know that my male counterparts, even when they &lt;em&gt;sound&lt;/em&gt; totally (and sometimes absurdly) sure of themselves, they can&amp;rsquo;t possibly be so certain either! So I try to put myself in their state of mind and just fake it. If I don&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;sound technical enough&amp;rdquo;, I&amp;rsquo;d rather actually become more competent than merely sound like it, for example. That&amp;rsquo;s where my energy goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t really like games, either, where I have to put on a guise and deceive my audience. And obviously it can be backfire coming from a woman. A woman product manager without a background in software engineering. But I don&amp;rsquo;t have patience for that and I prefer to be my honest, authentic self.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So after dwelling on this for a couple of days, I think I&amp;rsquo;ve come up with a way to determine how to strike the right tone. I&amp;rsquo;ll rehearse for my husband. I&amp;rsquo;m 100% comfortable and safe saying what I truthfully believe in a confident way to him. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how this strategy works for me the next time I&amp;rsquo;m stuck on how to phrase something in an authoritative way that still sounds like me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, this isn&amp;rsquo;t really a theory informed blog post. It could be if I spent some minutes doing some research on gendered language in the workplace and maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll do that later. Even though as a linguist I feel a bit guilty about that, for now I wanted the gratification of finally publishing a new blog post after a few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you decide how &amp;ldquo;aggressive&amp;rdquo; to be at work?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reply&#34;&gt;Reply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow the conversation and discuss on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;How aggressive should you be at work? &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/ws9uK0ZFaj&#34;&gt;https://t.co/ws9uK0ZFaj&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; meg.ehh 🇨🇦 (@MeganRisdal) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MeganRisdal/status/1274184503880060928?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;June 20, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kaggle’s 5 remote-first tips for new WFHers</title>
      <link>https://www.meg.dev/posts/kaggle-wfh-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 14:51:50 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>hello@meg.dev (Meg Risdal)</author>
      <guid>https://www.meg.dev/posts/kaggle-wfh-tips/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was originally &lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/mrisdal/kaggle-s-5-remote-first-tips-for-new-wfhers-3a4g&#34;&gt;published on DEV&lt;/a&gt;. My teammate &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/vimota&#34;&gt;Victor Mota&lt;/a&gt; and I wrote it together. You can check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimota.me/writing&#34;&gt;his blog here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com/&#34;&gt;Kaggle&lt;/a&gt; is a unique team at Google. Unlike the vast majority of Google teams, our team is fully remote-first and distributed in offices (Google and home) across North America and Australia. When the spread of COVID-19 led to mandates to &lt;strong&gt;work from home (WFH)&lt;/strong&gt;, my coworker &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/vimota&#34;&gt;Victor&lt;/a&gt; and I saw an opportunity to share insights from our team to help others across Google adapt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we recently shared our top five remote-first tips with Cloud AI leadership, our parent organization within Google. Now, we want to share our advice with you! The advice we put together is based on the things that we believe either require the biggest behavior shift or stand the best chance of increasing productivity to address pain points in this time of transition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/_2DqxUWQbNQPDl30igL5GyIRl-M6v10c8FPBOYu43Yqq2mxWQL1coExNhqG8KmWOG0krhWrrdFX6inVwmRL-jddLqg37LE3qYkAIvaZo1EAKkvXdi2Tl-yk7weTMTalklXoKjSGa&#34;&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;_Victor and me presenting our WFH tips to WFH Google Cloud AI leaders … while WFH_&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, to establish a bit more context, I’ll share more about Kaggle. Our team is made up of about 50 members in engineering, marketing, product management, data science, design, etc. Kaggle has been remote-first for about a decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, our core values are important to framing how we approach remote-first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Low ego&lt;/strong&gt; because it facilitates trust and open communication&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User first&lt;/strong&gt; because it drives focus on important problems to solve&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agility&lt;/strong&gt; because it helps us make decisions quickly in ambiguity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may want to consider how you can leverage aspects of your team’s culture to reinforce WFH productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-1-default-open&#34;&gt;Tip #1: Default open&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-problem&#34;&gt;🙅‍♀️ Problem&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your team may be feeling isolated, out of the loop, and siloed. Team members may be communicating one on one but missing the sense of team and community. This can cause anything from miscommunications or dropped balls to serious tensions and degrading trust on your team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-remote-first-solution&#34;&gt;✅ Remote-first solution&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Default to communicating as openly and transparently as possible with your team. Make extensive use of public (to your team), readily accessible communication channels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-tactics-for-your-teams&#34;&gt;🛠 Tactics for your teams&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;deliberately-communicate-more-frequently-than-you-think-you-need-to&#34;&gt;Deliberately communicate more frequently than you think you need to&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Communicate more frequently. Also make sure you’re not simply shouting into a void, but ensure that your team hears and understands, as well. Make sure your calendar events and Google Docs are visible by all by default.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;share-meeting-summaries--action-items-in-a-public-to-your-team-venue&#34;&gt;Share meeting summaries / action items in a public (to your team) venue&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take good meeting notes and share out summaries or action items in a public venue. GitLab has more great remote meeting tips in their &lt;a href=&#34;https://about.gitlab.com/company/culture/all-remote/meetings/&#34;&gt;handbook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;if-you-repeat-something-verbally-in-11s-write-it-down-in-a-google-doc-and-share&#34;&gt;If you repeat something verbally in 1:1s, write it down in a Google Doc and share&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t succumb to games of telephone. If something seems to be remotely important write it down. If your team doesn’t already formally document everything, this may make certain things feel more “official” than they might really be. The next tactic is one way to help make this adjustment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;make-wip-docs-available-for-input-from-more-people-earlier&#34;&gt;Make WIP docs available for input from more people earlier&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get feedback earlier on things in progress. Normally you would get feedback about ideas or projects in progress during “watercooler chat”. This is a way to replicate that and you might find that you even get more diverse and creative input.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/4ZoTo6RKCAYXLwF_RPvnBYdtN_Q0EQ_2diwx4_JHoBrdfTfd42fe45WctyDdpPcLw4XfgrslXSEzG3jpuiTk_aK_aPTAPDd0nHlTGKX3Tm47n9J9CDRNkWhipQWYR1_q63q7qwqB&#34;&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;_Making important documents easily accessible to anyone on the team_&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-2-practice-async-communication&#34;&gt;Tip #2: Practice async communication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-problem-1&#34;&gt;🙅‍♀️ Problem&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback loops are slow. Team members are AFK and unresponsive during typical working hours. This can slow projects down and leave people feeling frustrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-remote-first-solution-1&#34;&gt;✅ Remote-first solution&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Move more communication to async, setting norms and expectations so work still gets done efficiently. Kaggle’s team is distributed across many time zones so this is really important for us. Your teams may not be so distributed as ours, but at a time when so many team members’ schedules are becoming unpredictable or shifted, async can be critical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-tactics-for-your-teams-1&#34;&gt;🛠 Tactics for your teams&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;agree-on-team-wide-expectations-around-hours-of-communication-and-availability&#34;&gt;Agree on team-wide expectations around hours of communication and availability&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agreeing on team-wide expectations around hours of communication and availability. If you haven’t already done this, this is absolutely step 1! For inspiration, checkout GitLab’s handbook on &lt;a href=&#34;https://about.gitlab.com/handbook/communication/&#34;&gt;communication guidelines&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;know-when-to-move-from-async-to-sync&#34;&gt;Know when to move from async to sync&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, to the extent possible, be willing to quickly jump into a call if something doesn’t seem resolvable via chat. This means keeping a headset handy. This is especially useful in cases where you might feel things are tense or something is getting lost in translation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;create-a-venue-like-chat-for-async-daily-standup&#34;&gt;Create a venue like chat for async daily standup&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, if you’re worried about making sure you know what everyone on the team is working on, create a venue for this. We have a chat channel called #nikodaily where people share 1. What they did today. 2. What they’re doing tomorrow. 3. Any blockers. 4. Any FYIs. Create something that works for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/88aW56hNbTBU4fGNzyRbdLV6kEIPGh0soArqSLbczHXql8FyVxsbFampHNWWjc45FSaM-HXkHmQ3Ija38m5AdNqhHzAInAlv5ouea35th2EM_hM_pHrrjjlqGxQ7lBw30GekDtKm&#34;&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;_Our internal Niko Daily tool which records our async standup statuses and notes_&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-3-embrace-a-non-linear-workflow&#34;&gt;Tip #3: Embrace a non-linear workflow&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-problem-2&#34;&gt;🙅‍♀️ Problem&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without the ability to just walk over to someone and ask a question, team members are blocked and not making progress on a task, frustrated they can’t get immediate help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-remote-first-solution-2&#34;&gt;✅ Remote-first solution&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tip applies especially to engineering teams. For engineers who bristle at lots of meetings and context switches, productivity is normally associated with finding flow on a single task. That’s not always possible in a remote, distributed context. Similarly to async communication, a remote workflow expects non-linear progress and optimizes for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-tactics-for-your-teams-2&#34;&gt;🛠 Tactics for your teams&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;have-multiple-tasks-that-you-can-switch-between-to-always-ensure-progress&#34;&gt;Have multiple tasks that you can switch between to always ensure progress&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the asynchronous nature of remote work and especially with current unpredictable circumstances, try to have more than one task on the go, that you can switch between if you get blocked on your current task. At the same time, avoid having so many ongoing tasks at once that context switching prevents making any progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;document-and-make-team-knowledge-searchable-to-minimize-pings&#34;&gt;Document and make team knowledge searchable to minimize pings&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since you and your teammates may be focused on different things or available at different times, before pinging someone and potentially interrupting their workflow, check if your question has been answered in one of your public channels. One of the benefits of defaulting to open is that all your team knowledge is written down and searchable!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;provide-lots-of-context&#34;&gt;Provide lots of context&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you’re blocked and waiting for someone’s response, give plenty of context on what you’ve tried and what you understand so far so they can unblock you while you’re working on something else. Likewise, when responding to others, be deliberate about unblocking them. For example when making decisions or reviewing code, if possible give approval with conditions so they can progress without another round trip to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-4-foster-team-bonding&#34;&gt;Tip #4: Foster team bonding&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-problem-3&#34;&gt;🙅‍♀️ Problem&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morale is low and team members feel lonely and disconnected from each other. Tensions might emerge as trust weakens. People may feel less willing to take risks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-remote-first-solution-3&#34;&gt;✅ Remote-first solution&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many years, a Kaggler on our team, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com/jeffmoser&#34;&gt;Jeff Moser&lt;/a&gt;, has evangelized &lt;a href=&#34;https://stevemcconnell.com/&#34;&gt;Steve McConnell’s&lt;/a&gt; concept of the “half life of trust”. The longer you’re removed from aspects of your colleagues’ lives that make you realize who they are outside of work, the lower your trust is with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href=&#34;https://rework.withgoogle.com/blog/five-keys-to-a-successful-google-team/&#34;&gt;study on Google team effectiveness&lt;/a&gt;, psychological safety was the number one factor contributing to team success. Psychological safety requires trust, so for remote teams for whom this is harder to build, you have to be very deliberate about cultivating it. Put effort into unique ways to maintain and strengthen personal bonds. And have fun. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-tactics-for-your-teams-3&#34;&gt;🛠 Tactics for your teams&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;celebrate-wins-even-more-often&#34;&gt;Celebrate wins (even more) often!&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, celebrate wins more often. We use chat to regularly share wins in our largest team channel. If your company has a peer recognition system, encourage your team to use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;set-up-socialization-spaces-for-watercooler-chat&#34;&gt;Set up socialization spaces for “watercooler” chat&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, set up spaces to replace watercooler chat. These can be a combination of async (e.g., chat) and sync (e.g., recurring optional team meetings).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;use-emojis-gratuitously-seriously-&#34;&gt;Use emojis gratuitously (seriously!) 🤪&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, it might sound like a joke (okay, it’s a little tongue-in-cheek), but don’t forget to use emojis! By this, I really mean make sure you find ways to insert &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phatic_expression&#34;&gt;phatic&lt;/a&gt; expressions that are often missing from text-based communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/50Lgie0JK1SX5q89hTcP_XdcFyUAOwXrkUMJteN-KwdUCkPkrkdHE_Whno8Bzs0OWc3TaWIHow404nYboDBuAgIDkRx9yS1-9bv8w84-EjC34co6ZPW_SnpClpuG7ReDJVcpkKDv&#34;&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;_A sampling of posts from our some of our many interest-based chat channels like #pets, #random, and #booksandmovies_&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-5-take-care-of-yourself&#34;&gt;Tip #5: Take care of yourself&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our last bit of advice is to take care of yourself and encourage your teams to do the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we all know this is not a normal work from home situation. Even for our team, one that’s been remote for almost a decade, some of us are feeling the impact on our well being and productivity. In fact, we know from experience that some folks may respond to a situation like this by working even harder than usual. We have to give ourselves and each other a break.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a LOT of good advice already out there for well being and work-life balance. But here are some tips from our team. You should strive to do them to the extent possible, but it may be harder for some given circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/VUvXqngZRbA474lJqLYUX5kvRFpLqafGoTkvIZuE7ON54P2343dvu7_3ZEi4P6n-GVvxyU4PlKLrOUSFsSWQYXlAt_HjXhu1Fu4BAXY1_rfRd1BVoT4checRaBMnLyEsOLAfeSaX&#34;&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;_This is not normal_&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-tactics-for-your-teams-4&#34;&gt;🛠 Tactics for your teams&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;establish-clear-work-boundaries&#34;&gt;Establish clear work boundaries&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a routine of “going to the office” like get showered and dressed, maybe exercise to start the day. Also have a wind down routine for “going home” for example go for a walk. Try to have a dedicated space for work only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;disconnect-by-creating-a-predictable-schedule&#34;&gt;Disconnect by creating a predictable schedule&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disconnecting requires finding or creating predictability. For example, try to work the same regular hours. Snooze or disable notifications when you’re done working. And make sure your working hours are visible to others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;assume-good-intent&#34;&gt;Assume good intent&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, assume good intent from those you’re working with. This is an extremely taxing time for many and patience can more easily wear thin and mistakes will be made. Be understanding and compassionate (including with yourself!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wrapping-up&#34;&gt;Wrapping up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope that you find these tips helpful. Even for us, a seasoned remote-first team, improving our productivity, efficiency, and happiness is a perpetual process. We’re constantly redefining our own best practices, habits, and workflows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our most important tip for how to apply these recommendations is to be introspective and flexible. At the end of the day, we can’t give any one-size-fits-all advice because it doesn’t exist. Take the time as a team to listen to your own needs and pain points and adapt solutions accordingly. You’ll quickly find that you’ll develop norms that work for your style, culture, and situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’d love to hear in the comments what things work for you and your team!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reply&#34;&gt;Reply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow the conversation and discuss on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Want to know how &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/kaggle?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@kaggle&lt;/a&gt; does remote-first? &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/vimota?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@vimota&lt;/a&gt; and I share our top 5 remote-first tips for teams new to working from home! &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/remotework?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#remotework&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/c5HPDVUT9q&#34;&gt;https://t.co/c5HPDVUT9q&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; meg.ehh 🇨🇦 (@MeganRisdal) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MeganRisdal/status/1243578237994692608?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;March 27, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Productive transparency in online communities: Inspiration from trains and IKEA</title>
      <link>https://www.meg.dev/posts/transparency-in-online-communities/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 22:16:30 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>hello@meg.dev (Meg Risdal)</author>
      <guid>https://www.meg.dev/posts/transparency-in-online-communities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Japanese train system is famously fast, clean, friendly, and efficient. On the drive home from my first day back at Google I was reminded of why as I listened to the &lt;em&gt;99% Invisible&lt;/em&gt; podcast episode &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://99percentinvisible.org/episode/wait-wait-tell-me/&#34;&gt;“Wait wait &amp;hellip; tell me!”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. I’ll give you the tl;dr summary of the story and explain some connections I made to product development for online communities that got me so in my head I missed my exit for the 405.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the secrets to Japan’s impressive system of bullet trains, called &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shinkansen&#34;&gt;Shinkansen&lt;/a&gt;, is simple. It’s the kind of elegant solution I dream of and representative of the values I hold as a product and community person. In order to improve rider satisfaction with wait times while trains were cleaned, the new CEO of Shinkansen didn&amp;rsquo;t sacrifice quality. Instead he introduced transparency between workers who cleaned trains and waiting customers. He did this by literally making workers more visible (e.g., bright red uniforms) instead of intentionally invisible (pale blue uniforms that blend in with their environs). Beyond physical appearances alone, he also encouraged workers to actually speak with passengers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making their work more visible in these ways had profound effects on behaviors in the system between workers and waiting passengers. Namely, passengers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Were less frustrated by wait times because they could better see and understand the purpose of waiting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Empathized with workers to the point of being more conscientious by proactively cleaning up their own messes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this transparency, passengers were empowered with insight into the common interests between themselves and workers. They not only tolerated the extra wait as workers cleaned trains, they embraced it. And no one had to tell them “because it’s good for you.” Additionally, Shinkansen was able to maintain high standards of cleanliness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a conversation with a friend about the Shinkansen train system story, he brought up IKEA’s cafeterias. The ones with the amazing Swedish meatballs and lingonberry sauce. Where you bus your own table. Not only is a DIY approach appropriate here (it’s IKEA!), they make it consistently transparent throughout the diner’s “user journey” so there’s no room for unmet expectations for Michelin-grade experiences. And it goes beyond signs everywhere. The carts where you stash your emptied trays are an unmissable centerpiece of the cafe. In most places they are hidden out of sight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1517816630506-a8c5ccf61bf0?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjEyMDd9&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=crop&amp;amp;w=1050&amp;amp;q=80&#34; alt=&#34;Blue and yellow IKEA building&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://unsplash.com/photos/KDawdoaC-ts&#34;&gt;Photo by Oleg Laptev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;https://mrisdal.github.io/blog/posts/reflections-on-stack-overflow/&#34;&gt;my blog post&lt;/a&gt; reflecting on my time leading product for Stack Overflow’s public Q&amp;amp;A, I alluded to tensions among different types of users. Curators and moderators and question-askers and question-answerers. One of the things that I think is well appreciated by moderators and curators (and probably many question-answerers, too) is the importance of the quality of content that gets created and maintained over time. Interestingly, question-askers (mostly new users) are the driving force behind content creation on Stack Overflow, yet often their local and immediate needs may not make the quality of the entire repository present in mind. The tension, in part, in my opinion is a lack of transparency between integral parts of the system (people!) that could be communicating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the flow a question enters when it&amp;rsquo;s closed was more transparent, would that help people understand why it happens? If people saw how content reviews help keep up a healthy ecosystem of question and answer pairs, would they more eagerly contribute to review themselves? What if the average user knew that without a small number of volunteer moderators handling flagged content toxicity would be double what it is?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve long thought that much of Kaggle’s relative welcomingness as an online technical community is its inherent temporal transparency between power users and newcomers. This started with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com/competitions&#34;&gt;Competitions&lt;/a&gt;. Each Competition which runs for a couple of months is a new shared objective for new and old users alike to collaborate and share ideas. Each competition generates a cohort that’s basically a community of practice with a deadline. Once it’s over, users often write-up their approaches (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com/c/ashrae-energy-prediction/discussion/124984&#34;&gt;example&lt;/a&gt;), sharing what they learned with the community. And then they start all over again with the next competition. Over time, each user is on a cycling trajectory from novice to expert and there’s always some new technique or framework to learn as the state of the art in machine learning evolves. I really believe it&amp;rsquo;s visibility and participation in constantly cycling cohorts with shared goals that make it easier for users of all levels to better empathize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an online community, you need to find ways to foster and incentivize ways to encourage different types of users to interact positively and contribute to your mission. I believe that transparency, especially by making shared goals and opportunities to empathize apparent in the product itself, can be an important way to achieve this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thank you once again to Josh Heyer (AKA Shog9) for his feedback on this post (and for talking to me about delicious lingonberry sauce). Thanks also to my fellow Kaggle Noobs moderators (Aakash, Yifan, Mikel, Jorge) for their discussion on this topic.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reply&#34;&gt;Reply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow the conversation and discuss on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;I wrote up some thoughts on transparency in online communities. 👀🤗 &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/b4rEd0VA2i&#34;&gt;https://t.co/b4rEd0VA2i&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; meg.ehh 🇨🇦 (@MeganRisdal) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MeganRisdal/status/1220193165535170560?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;January 23, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on Stack Overflow: Building Successful Communities</title>
      <link>https://www.meg.dev/posts/reflections-on-stack-overflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 00:48:59 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>hello@meg.dev (Meg Risdal)</author>
      <guid>https://www.meg.dev/posts/reflections-on-stack-overflow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is my last day at Stack Overflow. For most of this year, I was the lead product manager for their flagship product, public Q&amp;amp;A. In my last couple of weeks there, I spent some time reflecting on what I have learned and how my perspectives as a product leader matured. As someone deeply invested in building open developer communities, I continue to refine my opinions about how to approach building community-facing products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on these reflections, the following is my own personal perspective on what a product leader at a place like Stack Overflow can do to be successful (and hence make community products successful). Although they are pretty specific to Stack Overflow, I am taking what I’ve learned with me to my next endeavor and you may find them applicable to your world, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make Stack Overflow work for &lt;strong&gt;everyone&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be ambitious and a driver of positive change in the face of inertia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The community is an asset. Experiment, iterate, and listen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create simple defaults and tear down configuration and customization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep the mission and impact in perspective always.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;building-a-successful-community&#34;&gt;Building a successful community&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;make-stack-overflow-work-for-everyone-do-not-indulge-us-versus-them-dynamics&#34;&gt;Make Stack Overflow work for everyone. Do not indulge “us versus them” dynamics.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many types of people who use Stack Overflow. The main segments for Public Q&amp;amp;A are: Askers (including people who just look up answers to existing questions), Answerers, Curators, and Moderators. The interesting thing about Stack Overflow’s user base though is that all of these segments (of real people!) interact with each other in feedback loops:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People ask questions and other people answer those questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Curators identify quality issues and other people receive that feedback&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People flag content that doesn’t belong on the site and moderators handle those flags&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any initiatives that only serve one segment put the community and product into imbalance. In reality you’re making changes in a complex, dynamical system of real people in a community. Emphasizing one type of user also makes things unnecessarily personal. By “personal” I mean about people, not about the system/software. I observed that this triggers an “us versus them” backlash which is not necessary and causes users to suffer. Instead, focus on the system itself and how all different kinds of users participate in it to interact with each other. I believe that this is an approach that will inherently make Stack Overflow more welcoming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/dUf-m_ircDT_3QXoWEnrVqZqv6FFPSvBHz8UOmSYKT8l2S_R4SQQaaXK35XJKpa9cK1CLM_XCq7Stet6M2Xktq17Id94uK88sZs282LvXhJ2L0pJlBxEjApSujLK8QSzw6YUXZZZ&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some things I kept in mind when thinking about how to make Stack Overflow work for everyone:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Always ask “How does this impact users?”&lt;/em&gt;. In specs/briefs I write, I always explicitly consider all participants in the relevant feedback loop. Going through this motion can uncover unanswered questions, highlights your thought process for readers, develops a muscle for user-focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Treat everyone as a valuable person as part of the system&lt;/em&gt;. Even if I’m working on something mainly designed to help one type of user, it can go a LONG ways both internally and externally to demonstrate care for everyone. Other people will pick sides or favorites, but you as the chief advocate for your users cannot succumb to this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Think holistically&lt;/em&gt;. I tend to like to think of user journeys in product work. For a given feature, how did users arrive there? What’s the next step? Considering all participants at each touchpoint in a user journey is a natural extension of this thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;be-ambitious-and-a-driver-of-positive-change-in-the-face-of-inertia-exude-optimism&#34;&gt;Be ambitious and a driver of positive change in the face of inertia. Exude optimism.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team focused on public Q&amp;amp;A is shockingly small: four IC developers. And the surface area of responsibility is enormous: all of Stack Overflow and the Stack Exchange network serving millions of people every month. Stack Overflow is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.alexa.com/topsites&#34;&gt;top 50 site in Alexa rankings&lt;/a&gt;. Having the impact the user base needs and deserves requires efficient use of resources paired with a healthy openness to risk. Otherwise it’s too easy to slip into conservative bug-fixing mode to just keep the status quo afloat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news is that the team is super capable when pushed to dream big. When I joined in early 2019, we made 7 internal commitments of which only 28% were hit. In October, we made 31 internal commitments and hit an 84% completion. This was possible despite receiving no additional developer resources during this timeframe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some tips for keeping functional teams productive and engaged:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Constantly clarify ambiguities&lt;/em&gt;. The biggest thing a product manager can do to help team productivity is clarify ambiguities. In the face of chaos or shifting priorities, the best thing you can do is make sure to shield the team as much as possible so they can stay focused on productive project work. In the day to day, stay engaged with what they’re working on and answer their questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Accentuate the positive&lt;/em&gt;. This team has historically been subjected to a lot of strife. Be empathetic, but do your best to sincerely highlight successes and positive motivators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Connect the team with end users&lt;/em&gt;. Making the team clearly see how their work has impact is a morale boost and motivator. Some ways to do this include inviting developers to join user interviews, reviewing and discussing research with a broad group of people, and holding project retrospectives that include preliminary data on feature performance. In a small example, I always included a user quote in the team’s weekly company-wide report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-community-is-an-asset-experiment-iterate-and-listen-to-your-users-the-whole-time&#34;&gt;The community is an asset. Experiment, iterate, and listen to your users the whole time.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rapid experimentation, incremental releases, and iteration is an opportunity to keep a dialogue with your users open. It’s a venue for you to not only involve them in the conversation, but to shape it by sharing and aligning on goals. Like I once told a coworker, “We’re both on different vectors. I share mine with you and you share yours with me and we both get a little closer and amplify our efforts.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of examples of this approach took place as part of our bigger efforts to improve experiences related to question closing. In one recent project, we worked to &lt;a href=&#34;https://meta.stackexchange.com/questions/337013/new-post-notices-rollout-on-stack-overflow&#34;&gt;ship the new post notices feature early&lt;/a&gt; and we were responsive to feedback from users. This led to making lots of small improvements before &lt;a href=&#34;https://meta.stackexchange.com/questions/339700/new-post-notices-are-live-network-wide&#34;&gt;rolling the change out more broadly&lt;/a&gt;. In another example, we &lt;a href=&#34;https://meta.stackoverflow.com/questions/388313/experiment-ended-closing-and-reopening-happens-at-3-votes-for-the-next-30-day&#34;&gt;engaged the community closely&lt;/a&gt; in testing different thresholds for voting to close and reopen questions, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://meta.stackoverflow.com/questions/390083/threshold-experiment-results-closing-editing-and-reopening-all-become-more-eff&#34;&gt;transparently sharing&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/stackoverflow/experiment-results-testing-close-reopen-thresholds-on-stack-overflow-5a35&#34;&gt;results of our experiments&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/MAKHGYl_QDfLybaA-x6I5adBck2kCXvchwVJqWv319TBIrb9hibjlDOjO7aZ8s9UrKfsHWISpE10udrKDKQ2QQyBl20bv683P5neVj4umt5zpere-0uWfvqa8ljT9jJzOKAE1zK4&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stack Overflow is a website with a huge user base. Not taking advantage of the ability to run tests and get feedback from enthusiastic community members is a missed opportunity. Do it in complement with other research methods. At the same time, these feedback loops threaten to slow things down and can be emotionally draining. Your mileage may vary (and a lot seems to depend on individual tastes), but here are some quick tips:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Don’t take things personally&lt;/em&gt;. You’ll get a lot of critique, positive and negative. As a product manager you have to emotionally separate yourself from the features you work on as much as possible. Instead, invest your energy into focusing on the objectives you share with end users and other stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Delegate communication&lt;/em&gt;. It can be exhausting and extremely time consuming to interact deeply with a critical audience. Lean on people who are experts at this. For example, you can try strategies like ghostwriting blog posts or asking others to synthesize feedback for you in a report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Take a principled stance&lt;/em&gt;. Decision-making is easier when you already have clear objectives and guiding product principles to use as heuristics. So form these early and lean on them aggressively to quickly resolve feedback rather than debating minutiae at length.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where appropriate, experimenting and iterating on ideas in public is also a great way to battle harden new features before introducing them to Teams customers, &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/teams&#34;&gt;Stack Overflow’s Private Q&amp;amp;A product&lt;/a&gt;. If something is successful at Stack Overflow’s scale, it may work for a company’s internal knowledge management, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;create-simple-defaults-and-tear-down-configuration-and-customization-do-not-try-to-please-everyone&#34;&gt;Create simple defaults and tear down configuration and customization. Do not try to please everyone.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stack Overflow is too complex. It’s hard to use for people who are not power users, it’s difficult to maintain for engineers, and it’s a challenge to design and build changes that work around tons of variants. This is not sustainable for such a small team with a huge mandate. For example, take &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/users/8157789/megan-risdal?tab=profile&#34;&gt;user profiles&lt;/a&gt;. They’re a mess of information overload, they’re bogged down with tons of settings and togglable preferences (some only used by a tiny number of people), and users can maintain unique profiles for each and every network site that they’re a member of. Then there’s the overall network profile. And chat profiles. Then profiles for Teams (private Q&amp;amp;A), too. Oh, and they’re not mobile responsive. Yuck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/MIAbOqg_Uccnlufi4Ubuos2FTc1fCe-1r1ZF2XUHu3eknZnGiN_Xg6B5WJMkp8RW54ILnF1V0WveZJgiNlVDXrWKnE-bPUnmvomfIUwzoNoiQXk0Kh3rlb7QGUfgjL8K9YB2Nizw&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking things away by simplifying them will be hard, but it’s necessary for the future of Stack Overflow. When I first joined Stack Overflow in March, the team launched the new &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.blog/2019/08/22/impact-of-ask-question-wizard/&#34;&gt;Ask Question Wizard&lt;/a&gt;. This created a whole new default question-asking flow for users with less than 111 reputation while other users had the old (10 years old) form intact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UX of the wizard was clunky. We heard this in feedback from a random sample of people who responded to our new monthly site satisfaction survey. And maintaining it AND the existing form was an immediate timesuck as we battled bugs and strange edge cases arising from technical workarounds required to support this complex feature. It wouldn’t surprise me if its measurable benefits actually stemmed from how hard it was to use. Therefore, we went back to the drawing board, taking what we learned from the wizard &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.blog/2019/09/26/research-update-improving-the-question-asking-experience/&#34;&gt;plus additional research&lt;/a&gt;, and launched a redesign of the question-asking form for everyone. The data (&lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.blog/2019/11/12/research-update-a-b-testing-the-new-question-form/&#34;&gt;quantitative&lt;/a&gt; and qualitative) and increased simplicity led us to consider it a huge improvement. Plus, it’s now way easier to iterate on (since of course it’s still not perfect!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do more to reduce forking paths and little used customizations. It’s not realistic to continue supporting these given extremely constrained resources and minimal benefit to users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This web of time – the strands of which approach one another, bifurcate, intersect or ignore each other through the centuries – embraces every possibility. We do not exist in most of them. In some you exist and not I, while in others I do, and you do not.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;― Jorge Luis Borges, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/work/quotes/14566729&#34;&gt;The Garden of Forking Paths&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some tips for approaching this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Make data-driven decisions&lt;/em&gt;. Use data (quantitative and qualitative) at every level to inform how you solve this problem. Use data to prioritize which things to tackle first and then use data to decide what configurations are most important, for instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Involve all stakeholders in decision-making&lt;/em&gt;. You really, really have to know who is dependent on something and how when you’re planning to take it away. Make sure to involve the right people in the conversation and, as much as possible, share the same data you have access to (and invite them to ask new questions, too).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have empathy&lt;/em&gt;. Loss aversion is a very real thing. Even if simplifying something is the best thing for users by all other accounts, taking something away still hurts. And this impacts not just end users, but the people who originally worked on a feature. You can have empathy by understanding how they use the feature and asking about the historical context around its original creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;keep-the-mission-and-impact-in-perspective-always&#34;&gt;Keep the mission and impact in perspective always.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With respect to mission, a lot of people are passionate about Stack Overflow and its community. There are a lot of loud voices and strong opinions pulling in many directions. Do what you can to keep focus on the bigger picture, both inside the team and externally. In this period of transition for the company, the mission is still being honed, but here are some things I personally believe to be important:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stack Overflow is a source of high quality question and answer pairs&lt;/strong&gt;. Do things that continue to grow this content, enrich it, and make it easier to access and use for all developers. But, Stack Overflow is not equivalent to Wikipedia. It’s not made up of facts frozen in time. More than a traditional encyclopedia, relevant information and practices in Stack Overflow’s community change as the developer landscape evolves. Make Stack Overflow a living, evolving library. It will never be “done”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make Stack Overflow for all developers&lt;/strong&gt;. It started as a place to serve programming enthusiasts and this was a successful way to catalyze the creation of a community and corpus of technical knowledge. Over time, it has clearly shown potential to make lives better for anyone who writes code. Figure out how to make Stack Overflow a place where anyone in the world who codes has a place to participate and learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With respect to impact, this is where it’s all too easy to fall into a trap of listening only to a small minority of people who enthusiastically offer their voices. These voices are super important to be sure, but they need to be balanced. In my time at Stack Overflow, we put a lot of effort into filling gaps in who we listened to. The vast majority of people who use Stack Overflow don’t have accounts (or aren’t logged-in) yet we had virtually no way to hear from them until we launched a &lt;a href=&#34;https://static.googleusercontent.com/media/research.google.com/en//pubs/archive/43221.pdf&#34;&gt;satisfaction tracking survey&lt;/a&gt; last summer. At the same time, we also strengthened ties between Community Management and product as a way to more scalably incorporate feedback from highly engaged users into the work we prioritized. They need to have a seat at the table in all of major feature work in order to continue to have a big impact on the solutions the team designs. They are experts on different types of user segments as well as the system and are critical to building Stack Overflow to better serve everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continue keeping impact in perspective and strive to better serve the needs of all types of users. It’s difficult, painful work because limited resources means important people may feel ignored. But I have confidence that progress will continue to be made on this front.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-conclusion&#34;&gt;In conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These beliefs are a reflection of my own personal values as a growing product leader who’s passionate about building great experiences for global developer communities, and as someone who has a great deal of optimism about the future of Stack Overflow. If I had to sum them up, I’d say I believe in unrelenting user focus and optimizing for global, rather than local, minima. I’m excited to take these values, along with everything I learned at Stack Overflow, with me in my next adventure: rejoining the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com/&#34;&gt;Kaggle&lt;/a&gt; team at Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thank you to Shog9, Donna Choi, and Julia Silge for their feedback on drafts of this post.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reply&#34;&gt;Reply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow the conversation and discuss on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Read my reflections on Stack Overflow and how my product thinking around building for communities has matured &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/FCKEXDlLKi&#34;&gt;https://t.co/FCKEXDlLKi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; meg.ehh 🇨🇦 (@MeganRisdal) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MeganRisdal/status/1203000660817367041?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;December 6, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Interview with Superlinguo: Linguists in Careers</title>
      <link>https://www.meg.dev/posts/superlinguo-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 00:29:18 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>hello@meg.dev (Meg Risdal)</author>
      <guid>https://www.meg.dev/posts/superlinguo-interview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.superlinguo.com/post/188176778397/linguistics-jobs-interview-with-a-product-manager&#34;&gt;cross-posted from an interview I recently did with Superlinguo&lt;/a&gt;, a language and linguistics blog by Lauren Gawne, for her excellent linguists in careers series.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Lauren:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of tech people I know say “the best skill a programmer can have is knowing how to look up the right answer on Stack Exchange” It’s one of those websites that people use every day, but perhaps without thinking about how it gets built. Megan Risdal is one of the people who make Stack Overflow happen, as a Product Manager leading Public Q&amp;amp;A. As Megan mentions below, there’s even a &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguistics.stackexchange.com/&#34;&gt;Linguistics Stack Exchange&lt;/a&gt; (you might just see some old &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguistics.stackexchange.com/users/64/laureng&#34;&gt;answers from me&lt;/a&gt; there). Megan has not only forged a career for herself in tech, she helps demystify the industry for other linguists who might follow in her footsteps, on Twitter (@MeganRisdal) and her &lt;a href=&#34;meg.dev&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://66.media.tumblr.com/05270b919fb9c719ff5cd491b37cbc67/16001c6a0b1b48e1-83/s500x750/b18e006454ce10d5d11c582767ff40371240094d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-did-you-study-at-university&#34;&gt;What did you study at university?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My undergraduate degree is in Psychology from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uwec.edu/&#34;&gt;University of Wisconsin, Eau Claire&lt;/a&gt; where my interests were in &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Differential_psychology&#34;&gt;individual differences&lt;/a&gt;. I also did a minor in French and this is where I first learned about linguistics as a field of study. My combined interests in language and individual differences psychology led me to completing a senior thesis project on variation in attitudes towards linguistic diversity. Just last year this work was published with my then advisor, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uwec.edu/profiles/bensonej/&#34;&gt;Dr. Erica Benson&lt;/a&gt;, as a chapter in &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cambridge.org/us/academic/subjects/languages-linguistics/sociolinguistics/language-regard-methods-variation-and-change?format=HB&#34;&gt;Language Regard: Methods, Variation, and Change&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From here, I did a Master’s degree in Sociolinguistics at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncsu.edu/&#34;&gt;North Carolina State University&lt;/a&gt;. Building on my statistics background from studying psychology, I dove deeper into quantitative methods, learning R along the way, while focusing on sociophonetics and laboratory phonology. For my capstone project, I measured articulatory (ultrasound tongue imaging), aerodynamic, (nasal/oral airflow), and acoustic variation in coarticulatory vowel nasalization strategies among Anglo-American and African American (Vernacular) English speakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I started a PhD at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ucla.edu/&#34;&gt;UCLA&lt;/a&gt; where I intended to continue studying laboratory phonology. I only ended up finishing one year which was spent on theoretical foundations, articulatory phonetics, and learnability before leaving with a second Master’s degree in Linguistics. I ended up deciding to leave academia because I was disillusioned already with the prospect of the job market and the limited potential for my work to have impact beyond academia. I made my mind up when I applied for a job at Google and got an interview. I ultimately failed, but this was enough for me to feel confident my resume was “good enough” (completely incidentally I ended up later getting hired and working at Google for a couple of years prior to my current role).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-your-job&#34;&gt;What is your job?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past six months I’ve been working as a Product Manager at &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/&#34;&gt;Stack Overflow&lt;/a&gt; where I lead the team working on public Q&amp;amp;A. If you’re not familiar with Stack Overflow, it’s a site where anyone who codes can come to find answers to their programming questions. We also have the Stack Exchange network which has similar Q&amp;amp;A sites for other topics like cooking and anime. There’s even a &lt;a href=&#34;https://linguistics.stackexchange.com/&#34;&gt;Linguistics Stack Exchange&lt;/a&gt; site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my day-to-day, as a product manager, I work closely with our developers, designers, researchers, data scientists, community managers, marketing, and leadership. So, it’s a lot of meetings and a lot of Google Docs. My job entails taking many, many inputs and synthesizing them into a strategy and product roadmap that the team executes on to make Stack Overflow a more useful, engaging place for all developers. On a given day, you could catch me writing a new feature specification for a developer, reviewing results of an experiment with our data scientists, or dropping in on user interviews. One of the things I love the most about my job is the variety. If a project is slipping or we just don’t have the resources for something important, I’m the person who can step in and do what it takes to make sure the work of my collaborators adds up to something successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-does-your-linguistics-training-help-you-in-your-job&#34;&gt;How does your linguistics training help you in your job?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My training in linguistics absolutely helps me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, and most importantly I believe, my background in sociolinguistics has taught me the significance of diversity among groups of people (like users of a product) in so many ways. For example, Stack Overflow sees many millions of users every month, but we know that not everyone is equally likely to participate on the site. There are huge, intimidating barriers to participation which disproportionately impact different groups of people depending on things like their background and experience coding. So every day I think about how changes to the product will affect different types of users. Me and my team are constantly striving to better understand the important ways our users vary in their backgrounds, motivations, and pain points and how we can better meet their needs. Especially in a globally diverse online community like ours where users interact and community with each other it’s extremely important for me and my colleagues to think about always.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, and more concretely, the quantitative methods and experimental best practices I acquired while studying linguistics are highly applicable to my day-to-day job. We make use of a lot of different qualitative and quantitative research methods at Stack Overflow and having training in this area allows me to leverage these resources effectively in my product decision-making. Before I joined Stack Overflow, I had also spent some time as a data scientist, so my background in statistics and R was extremely relevant there. Without this training, I don’t think I would be where I am today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;do-you-have-any-advice-do-you-wish-someone-had-given-to-you-about-linguisticscareersuniversity&#34;&gt;Do you have any advice do you wish someone had given to you about linguistics/careers/university?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I’m very happy with my trajectory. I’m extremely grateful to everyone who supported me at every stage and I would not be where I am today without all of these experience (yes including dropping out of a PhD!). That said, some thing that I wish I had encountered sooner are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seriously, build a public portfolio. Make your work visible. Curate an online presence. Having even a just a modest &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MeganRisdal&#34;&gt;Twitter following&lt;/a&gt; and some publicly discoverable content with my name on it has helped me immeasurably in my career. Oh, and learn git.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pay &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; attention to what’s going on outside of your academic bubble. I fully intended to stay in academia when I started my PhD at UCLA. Had I thought somewhat ahead of time about the possibility that I would end up industry, I may have prioritized different classes or perhaps even chosen a different PhD program altogether. For example, if you have a choice between learning OCaml and Python, maybe see what non-academia has to say, too, as an input to your decision. Then again, hindsight is 2020. I would have seriously regretted not taking statistics/research methods under any circumstances, though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;any-other-thoughts-or-comments&#34;&gt;Any other thoughts or comments?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think every tech company should look to hire people trained in linguistics. There are so, so many ways in which a background in linguistics is relevant to so many careers in tech. From user research to data science to (apparently) product management, a background in linguistics adds a unique and valuable perspective. If you’re not sure what you’re qualified for, carefully tailor your experience, cast your net wide, and seek out advice!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more interviews on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.superlinguo.com/&#34;&gt;Superlinguo&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reply&#34;&gt;Reply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow the conversation and discuss on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;My Interview with &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/superlinguo?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@superlinguo&lt;/a&gt;: Linguists in Careers &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/crosspost?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#crosspost&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/BVO9nK3v84&#34;&gt;https://t.co/BVO9nK3v84&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; meg.ehh 🇨🇦 (@MeganRisdal) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MeganRisdal/status/1202825630632439809?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;December 6, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Know Nothing</title>
      <link>https://www.meg.dev/posts/how-to-know-nothing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 17:00:27 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>hello@meg.dev (Meg Risdal)</author>
      <guid>https://www.meg.dev/posts/how-to-know-nothing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of months ago I started a new job as a product manager at Stack Overflow. This blog post is about how to know nothing in a new job. It&amp;rsquo;s about that whiplash-like experience of going from confidently knowing everything there is to know about your work to coming to a grinding to halt so you can start all over again from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://frinkiac.com/video/S09E19/TZFO4rsFaIkVsYcDt05xmH3LkhE=.gif&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, maybe it&amp;rsquo;s not so dramatic as that, but the insecure feelings I was having inspired me to ask for advice from my Twitter followers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Going from knowing everything and a half at one job to starting fresh is rough. Anyone have any tips for feeling better about it?&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; meg.ehh 🇨🇦 (@MeganRisdal) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MeganRisdal/status/1120880418562002945?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;April 24, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To give some more background, I was feeling especially daunted by my own lack of knowledge for a couple of reasons, I think:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com/mrisdal&#34;&gt;Kaggle&lt;/a&gt; (my previous job) I worked through a really exciting high growth period. When I started in 2016, they were focused mainly on competitions and towards the end of my time there we had massively expanded the community, the product, and the team. We even lived through a successful acquisition by Google. I was present as a participant, either as a &amp;ldquo;witness&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;creator&amp;rdquo;, in all of this change. I felt that I could competently answer just about any question someone (internal or external) could ask me about Kaggle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, the company I&amp;rsquo;ve joined (&lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/users/8157789/megan-risdal?tab=profile&#34;&gt;Stack Overflow&lt;/a&gt;) is quite a bit like Kaggle in that it has a large, technical userbase with a rich history of cultural norms and past product decisions. That rich history has made Stack Overflow the household brand it is today, but it can feel intimidating as someone who wasn&amp;rsquo;t an active participant in it over the years. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot of tribal knowledge to catch up on!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, for this blog post I wanted to summarize some of the great advice I got from folks on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-its-normal-and-okay-to-feel-insecure&#34;&gt;1. It&amp;rsquo;s normal and okay to feel insecure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is worth mentioning up front! I got a number of replies from people either expressing solidarity or assuring me it&amp;rsquo;s a normal feeling for anyone starting a new job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Any time one starts a new job, it is completely normal to feel overwhelmed and insecure about your knowledge. Remember, starting out fresh is overwhelming for anyone. It&amp;#39;s completely normal for people to take 60-90 days to get up to speed.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Just remember you are kickass!&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; JSON Baumgartner (@jasonbaumgartne) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jasonbaumgartne/status/1121099345535864842?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;April 24, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-remind-yourself-you-were-competent-and-you-will-be-again&#34;&gt;2. Remind yourself you were competent and you will be again&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is for those of us that laugh at the idea of ever succumbing to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dunning%E2%80%93Kruger_effect&#34;&gt;Dunning–Kruger effect&lt;/a&gt; when it comes to evaluating our own competence. I&amp;rsquo;ll admit that I requested my personnel file when leaving Google so I have my performance reviews to remind me that I &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; kick ass at my job in some objective-ish sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like this reply from someone else who recently changed teams:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;I mean j still feel hella dumb.. but I know I feel dumb because I&amp;#39;m learning new things. Which helps me realize I&amp;#39;m not really dumb. It&amp;#39;s just how I feel.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Fred v3.0.0 🤖🎸 (@ProbNotABot) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ProbNotABot/status/1121188776250888192?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;April 24, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-lean-into-your-newbie-perspective-as-superpower&#34;&gt;3. Lean into your newbie perspective as superpower&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was probably my favorite reply (from a former colleague at Google):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;It helps when people remind me that being new to a company/role/tech area is a super power. You have fresh eyes, new perspectives, ideas for connections not yet made.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Keep wearing those newbie cuffs of power as long as you can!&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Madame Secretary commandasaurus 🦖 (@amcasari) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/amcasari/status/1120881183552757760?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;April 24, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was also stated nicely by another person who &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ztuylime/status/1121132899166605312&#34;&gt;replied with this quote&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the beginner&amp;rsquo;s mind there are many possibilities,
but in the expert&amp;rsquo;s there are few
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dailyzen.com/journal/zen-mind-beginners-mind&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shunryu Suzuki&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because I know I have a lot to learn in my new role, I&amp;rsquo;ve had an amazing opportunity to ask &amp;ldquo;Why?&amp;rdquo; so many times. I&amp;rsquo;m definitely going to keep wearing this hat for as long as I can as I talk to both coworkers &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MeganRisdal/status/1127006719492509701?s=20&#34;&gt;as well as users&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/aCraigPfeifer/status/1121089455538999297&#34;&gt;As someone else replied&lt;/a&gt;, by challenging assumptions you&amp;rsquo;re &amp;ldquo;both learning about the environment and moving it forward.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-be-vulnerable&#34;&gt;4. Be vulnerable&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People can only help you if they know what you&amp;rsquo;re struggling with or how you want to improve. Maybe it wasn&amp;rsquo;t comfortable for me to tweet the world about not knowing everything, but it got me some amazing replies that can hopefully help even more people than just myself. Plus, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/richwag/status/1120907365157625856&#34;&gt;as someone replied&lt;/a&gt;, &amp;ldquo;If you don&amp;rsquo;t feel uncomfortable you&amp;rsquo;re not learning.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;I dunno, I&amp;#39;ve really struggled to have this kind of vulnerability in my new gig and I think I&amp;#39;ve come off as a know-it-all asshole at times. I think you&amp;#39;re winning 😁&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Justin Kiggins (@neuromusic) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/neuromusic/status/1120915698350321664?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;April 24, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This also ties in well with &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/tinkertim/status/1120887904287494145&#34;&gt;some other advice I got&lt;/a&gt; to request feedback early and often as a newcomer to a team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve distilled the advice I got into the several different themes I wrote about above, but at the end of the day my two biggest takeaways are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be patient with yourself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be inquisitive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And eventually you &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; know something again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reply&#34;&gt;Reply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow the conversation and discuss on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;How to know nothing &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/awlln2Y3b7&#34;&gt;https://t.co/awlln2Y3b7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; meg.ehh 🇨🇦 (@MeganRisdal) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MeganRisdal/status/1127699988551626752?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;May 12, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Product Management as an Episode of Black Mirror</title>
      <link>https://www.meg.dev/posts/product-management-as-an-episode-of-black-mirror/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 01:43:59 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>hello@meg.dev (Meg Risdal)</author>
      <guid>https://www.meg.dev/posts/product-management-as-an-episode-of-black-mirror/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Being a product manager on a small remote, distributed team reminds me a lot of the Black Mirror episode, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Be_Right_Back&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Be Right Back&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the sci-fi anthology series, a woman uses an AI service to bring back her recently deceased partner. She does so by uploading all of their text messages, emails, voicemails, and any other computer-mediated conversation she shared with him to the, uhh, Cloud I suppose. That&amp;rsquo;s one use case for GDPR data requests! All of this data was then used to train a super language model to embody (literally) a clone of her prematurely departed husband.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what does this have to do with being a product manager on a remote, distributed team? The sheer volume of written text I produce, of course! So much you could nearly hope to train a clone of me someday, language model and all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://source.unsplash.com/eOSqRq2Qm1c/800x450&#34;&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;_Photo by David Clode on Unsplash_&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On remote, distributed teams, asynchronous, high quality communication is essential. Now, I &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; have experience working on remote, distributed teams (so nothing to compare it to), but hopefully this becomes more of the norm. And in any case I think there are a lot of great reasons to write and write a LOT as a product manager. And ideally, you write in a way that faithfully transfers your product thinking, insights, and vision faithfully to Google Docs text and formatting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few reasons why I think Black Mirror worthy documentation should be a best practice regardless of whether you&amp;rsquo;re colocated and shoulder-to-shoulder or if multiple timezones separate you and your closest collaborators:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A no-brainer (maybe literally if this catches on): Clearly written specs should enable my coworkers to focus on building uninterrupted as much as possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Propaganda!&amp;rdquo; Framing my artifacts up-front with context which is an opportunity to weave a consistent thread in the story I want to weave for our product&amp;rsquo;s direction. It then becomes a story I can trust my team to internalize.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s like designing a redundant system&amp;hellip; if I make myself partly redundant through documentation, I might be able to afford to spend some of my time on a bit of extra higher level strategy and planning here and there. ;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So there you go, that&amp;rsquo;s why being a product manager at a remote, distributed company is like being in an episode of Black Mirror (except in a good way!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reply&#34;&gt;Reply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow the conversation and discuss on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Product management as an episode of Black Mirror &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/SSvu9lgbUV&#34;&gt;https://t.co/SSvu9lgbUV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; meg.ehh 🇨🇦 (@MeganRisdal) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MeganRisdal/status/1115500289891557377?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;April 9, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Amass Engineering Knowledge as a Product Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.meg.dev/posts/amassing-swe-knowledge-as-a-pm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 23:50:25 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>hello@meg.dev (Meg Risdal)</author>
      <guid>https://www.meg.dev/posts/amassing-swe-knowledge-as-a-pm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For about the past two years, I&amp;rsquo;ve been a product manager at Kaggle where I work on our public data platform as well as (more recently) our Google Cloud Platform integrations team. Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve had the opportunity to do quite a bit of reflection on my career thanks in part to having a mentee (being a mentor is awesome!). The other day she asked me how I &amp;ldquo;amassed as much engineering knowledge as I have&amp;rdquo;. (She asks great questions!) I shared &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MeganRisdal/status/1096583566190731264?s=20&#34;&gt;my answer on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and, you know what, I want to blog more so I&amp;rsquo;m sharing it here, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I had to spend a few days thinking about how to respond in a sage, mentor-ly way because it hasn&amp;rsquo;t been something I was necessarily intentional about (my interest in software development is more of a curiosity, probably). At the same time, I definitely had a couple of motivators for accumulating engineering knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Product managers spend their days influencing without authority. Understanding and sympathizing with your engineering coworkers can help with this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apart from the website about goldfish I made when I was 12, I don&amp;rsquo;t already have a background in computer science or software development. I could elaborate on why exactly I include this, but I&amp;rsquo;ll save that for another time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After thinking about her question for a bit and jotting down my thoughts in my favorite note-taking app, Sublime Text, here&amp;rsquo;s what I came up with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-invest-time-to-learn-what-it-takes-to-describe-architecture-and-key-services-at-a-high-level&#34;&gt;1. Invest time to learn what it takes to describe architecture and key services at a high level&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a good idea for two reasons. First, this information should be readily accessible in some form&amp;ndash;take advantage of it! Just ask for the documentation for it or, if necessary, schedule a chat with the owner engineer. Second, this will be one of the highest leverage ways to successfully gauge feasibility of new features. This has saved me a number of times from needing to bother our tech leads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To give an example, when our tech lead was on paternity leave last Northern hemisphere fall, I took over managing our engineering team. Early on, we began experiencing a lot of instability with one of our services. I took the time then to review all of the available architecture and desgin docs (and even a 1hr recorded onboarding video!). From this I was able to draft a design doc proposing specific changes which were ultimately implemented (with a lot of input from my coworkers, of course!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-read-engineering-design-docs-for-fun-especially-requirements-and-alternatives-considered&#34;&gt;2. Read engineering design docs for fun, especially requirements and alternatives considered&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s fun, I promise! This is a lot like #2, but it&amp;rsquo;s more about understanding the process, context, and conversation that happens around engineering designs. Plus understanding what&amp;rsquo;s important and why to your coworkers is a great way to empathize with them. And of course, it can also ensure you&amp;rsquo;re up-to-date on things like database schema changes, new services, etc. that might help you answer questions or inspire product ideas in the future. It&amp;rsquo;s helped me in this way a number of times!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-ask-swes-you-work-with-for-more-technical-details-than-you-may-actually-need&#34;&gt;3. Ask SWEs you work with for more technical details than you may actually need&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See, these are all so easy! Even if it&amp;rsquo;s out of pure curiosity that I ask for additional technical details, doing so is a great way to test my knowledge and show my coworkers I care about understanding the problems they&amp;rsquo;re solving. I&amp;rsquo;ve found that my developer coworkers are always more than happy to share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-have-and-sometimes-use-a-development-environment-like-your-coworkers&#34;&gt;4. Have (and sometimes use!) a development environment like your coworkers&#39;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing this might be relatively minor and is probably not necessary in all (or maybe most) cases, but it&amp;rsquo;s given me a lot of appreciation for how much our team invests in developer productivity and dev tooling. I like knowing how to make minor changes and deploy them. And my coworkers that helped me out liked seeing me contribute to our codebase and were super happy to help. I set up the server-side C# code that creates the CSVs we use for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com/kaggle/meta-kaggle&#34;&gt;Meta Kaggle&lt;/a&gt;, Kaggle&amp;rsquo;s public dataset about &amp;hellip; Kaggle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so there&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve come up with to answer my coworker&amp;rsquo;s question. I&amp;rsquo;m still learning, but these are nonetheless some things that have helped me do my job better (and enjoy it more). The common thread my pieces of advice share, I think, is that they exhibit care for my coworkers, the things they work on, and how they make decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My final piece of meta advice from here is to demonstrate that you&amp;rsquo;re listening and working on improving your engineering knowledge. The more you make product decisions with the things you learned through the help of your coworkers as input, the more people will come to trust you. And in turn, they&amp;rsquo;ll share more with you. It&amp;rsquo;s a really rewarding cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be curious. Be empathetic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reply&#34;&gt;Reply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow the conversation and discuss on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;How to amass SWE knowledge as a PM | &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/XpBjapQn3a&#34;&gt;https://t.co/XpBjapQn3a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; meg.ehh 🇨🇦 (@MeganRisdal) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MeganRisdal/status/1098104382569078784?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;February 20, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>