<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>women in tech on Meg Risdal</title>
    <link>https://www.meg.dev/tags/women-in-tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in women in tech on Meg Risdal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>hello@meg.dev (Meg Risdal)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>hello@meg.dev (Meg Risdal)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 19:47:01 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.meg.dev/tags/women-in-tech/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Be aggressive, be be aggressive. But how aggressive?</title>
      <link>https://www.meg.dev/posts/be-aggressive/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 19:47:01 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>hello@meg.dev (Meg Risdal)</author>
      <guid>https://www.meg.dev/posts/be-aggressive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week I asked for feedback on something I wrote from a trusted colleague. My audience was larger than usual for me and 100% men (as far as I knew). Although I&amp;rsquo;m already pretty confident in my prose-writing skills, I felt greater than usual pressure to make a compelling, tight story. I wanted what I wrote to sound authoritative and well informed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My colleague gave me great constructive feedback and overall really liked what I wrote. Except one spot where I came across as harsh and somewhat arrogant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cringed. &lt;em&gt;I know, I know&lt;/em&gt;. When drafting that particular point, I had literally thought to myself (knowing that I can tend to hedge too much) &amp;ldquo;Okay, try to sound very assertive and &lt;em&gt;masculine&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;rdquo; It wasn&amp;rsquo;t me. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t my style or my voice. And it ended up sounding too abrasive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, easy enough fix. I softened the language and sent it off to my co-authors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, I kept thinking about this. It really made me realize how I&amp;rsquo;m constantly monitoring how I speak and write to perfectly balance cold authority and warm personability. Whether I&amp;rsquo;m self conscious about the number of &amp;ldquo;:)&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;!&amp;rdquo; that I use in an email or my willingness to admit &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know&amp;rdquo; in a meeting, it&amp;rsquo;s a perpetual struggle against my natural tendencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing is, I rarely actually feel 100% confident. But I know that my male counterparts, even when they &lt;em&gt;sound&lt;/em&gt; totally (and sometimes absurdly) sure of themselves, they can&amp;rsquo;t possibly be so certain either! So I try to put myself in their state of mind and just fake it. If I don&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;sound technical enough&amp;rdquo;, I&amp;rsquo;d rather actually become more competent than merely sound like it, for example. That&amp;rsquo;s where my energy goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t really like games, either, where I have to put on a guise and deceive my audience. And obviously it can be backfire coming from a woman. A woman product manager without a background in software engineering. But I don&amp;rsquo;t have patience for that and I prefer to be my honest, authentic self.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So after dwelling on this for a couple of days, I think I&amp;rsquo;ve come up with a way to determine how to strike the right tone. I&amp;rsquo;ll rehearse for my husband. I&amp;rsquo;m 100% comfortable and safe saying what I truthfully believe in a confident way to him. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how this strategy works for me the next time I&amp;rsquo;m stuck on how to phrase something in an authoritative way that still sounds like me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, this isn&amp;rsquo;t really a theory informed blog post. It could be if I spent some minutes doing some research on gendered language in the workplace and maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll do that later. Even though as a linguist I feel a bit guilty about that, for now I wanted the gratification of finally publishing a new blog post after a few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you decide how &amp;ldquo;aggressive&amp;rdquo; to be at work?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reply&#34;&gt;Reply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow the conversation and discuss on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;How aggressive should you be at work? &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/ws9uK0ZFaj&#34;&gt;https://t.co/ws9uK0ZFaj&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; meg.ehh 🇨🇦 (@MeganRisdal) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MeganRisdal/status/1274184503880060928?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;June 20, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>